<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic on Academic</title>
    <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016-2018 Shaoqing Dai</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/mycv/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>List of News</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug. 1, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the Applied Energy Summer School 2018 at Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May. 25,2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 11th Chinese R Language Conference and presented the study of geographical detector at
Renmin University, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May.22, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 13th International Symposium of Spatial Accuracy, Spatial Accuracy 2018, Spatial Accuracy Assessment
in Natural Resources and Environmental Sciences and presented the study of high resolution carbon dioxide emissions mapping at
China National Convention Center, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May. 21, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the workshop of Machine Learning Algorithms for Spatial Data at Institute of Geographic Sciences and Natural
Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mar. 26, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
The results by integrating forest management patches inventory, remote sensing and GIS indicated that the elevation and species
had a significant effect on PM2.5 in urban forest. The interactions between the human activities and other ecological factors
were the non-linear enhancement. &lt;a href=&#34;../publication/2018-03-26/&#34;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; is now available on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mdpi.com/2072-4292/10/4/521&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mar. 22, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai won the the national winning award on 2017 “Sharing Cup” College Student Science and Technology Resource
Sharing Service Innovation Contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb. 15, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;:
We used the panel data analyze the eﬀects of command-and-control and market-oriented policy tools on China’s energy
conservation and emissions reduction innovation. &lt;a href=&#34;../publication/2018-02-15/&#34;&gt;This Chinese paper&lt;/a&gt; published on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cpre.sdnu.edu.cn/WKC/WebPublication/paperDigest.aspx?paperID=e08627b9-4786-4236-9c4d-f558b23cf875&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;China Populaiton, Resources and Environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec. 27, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
We used the panel data analyze the eﬀects of command-and-control and market-oriented policy tools on China’s energy
conservation and emissions reduction innovation. &lt;a href=&#34;../publication/2017-12-27/&#34;&gt;This English paper&lt;/a&gt; published on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10042857.2017.1418273&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chinese Journal of Populaiton Resources and Environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec. 16, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
We explored the relationship between the Carbon Dioxide Emission and fragmentation of urban functional landscape.
The abstract and poster were accepted and showed at the American Geophysical Union(AGU) Fall Meeting, New Orleans, America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec. 4, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Our research determined the association between the area of submersion and the change area of landscape by data mining.
Using the change in ecology indices, we ascertained the changing spatial patterns of the NGI landscape and used these
findings to formulate suggestions for Sponge City planning in Fuzhou. Overall, our work combines three research themes,
urban waterlogging, landscape ecology, and data mining, for a deep analysis of the relationship between the NGI landscape
and storm runoff in an urban environment. &lt;a href=&#34;../publication/2017-12-04/&#34;&gt;This paper&lt;/a&gt; published on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ascelibrary.org/doi/book/10.1061/9780784481042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Low Impact Development Conference China 2016 : LID Applications in Sponge City Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nov. 11, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 9th Chinese Landscape Eoclogy workshop, Landscape Ecology and Urban Sustainability and presented the
study of urban form and PM2.5 at Sanyuan hotel, Guangzhou, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct. 24, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 15th User Conference of esri as a volunteer of expericence zone at Beijing International
Convention Center, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct. 16, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai went to the nanjing university of information science &amp;amp; technology and learned the WRF model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sep. 28, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 2rd urban environment long-term monitor and sustainable development workshop, The seminar of National Key Research
and Development Plan and presented the study of the assement platform of urban forest ecosystem servcie based on InVEST model and IOT
at Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jun. 8, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the Academic Week of Tsinghua Urban Planning and Design Institute 2017 at Tsinghua Tongheng 16th floor atrium, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jun. 3, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 2017 BCL Annual Conference at Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May. 21, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 10th Chinese R Language Conference at Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May. 15, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Our poster about the relationship between the carbon dioxide emissions and fargmentation of urban functional landscape showed
at the The 9th Lecture of Modern Ecology, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apr. 8, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 10th Beijing Geographical Graduate Conference at Institute of Geographical Sciences and Natural
Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan. 13, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended courses of DSSAT model and remote sensing data assimilation by ZhongkeZihuan at Hongji hotel, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec. 23, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the Christmas Salon of Sustainable City·Transportation as a volunteer at Hutong of Shi&amp;rsquo;s Family, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nov. 27,2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the Workshop of 12th Spatial Behavior and Planning &amp;amp; Spatial-Temporal Behavior and Social Planning Research and presented the
study of crime geography at Beijing Union University, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct. 12, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 12th National Symposium of Biodiversity Science and Conservation as a volunteer at International
Convention Center, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sep. 22, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the courses of Biome-BGC model by ZhongkeZihuan at Hongji hotel, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sep. 8, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
Shaoqing Dai attended the 14th User Conference of esri at Beijing International Convention Center, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug. 26, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;:
We analyzed the survey of the safety of eletric bicycle as a volunteer of Green Bike-Transit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July. 1, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;：
Shaoqing Dai attented the 10th 10th annual conference of International Association of China Planning, Peking University, Beijing, China and presented
at the smart city and big data workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jun. 26, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;：
Our poster of sponge city research presented at the 2016 International Low Impact Development Conference, China National Convention Center, Beijing, China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3L Tool of NASA Satellite</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/d3l-tool-of-nasa-satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/d3l-tool-of-nasa-satellite/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite was developed by Mr. Dai . The program provides a graphical interface to download satellite imagery from NASA, such as MODIS products, MERIS and more. Due to new NASA Policies LAADS FTP servers (both public and private) will be shutting down around Monday, April 20th 2018. NASA provide some scripts to download, but it&amp;rsquo;s a little hard for some people who didn&amp;rsquo;t use python. So I have developed the D3L Tool of NASA Satellite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;download-link&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/D3LToolcn.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite 1.0 (4/27/2018) for 64-bit Windows 8，10, Chinese Vesion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/D3LToolen.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite 1.0 (4/27/2018) for 64-bit Windows 8，10, English Vesion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/D3LToolcnWin732bit.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite 1.0 (4/27/2018) for 32-bit Windows 7，8，10 Chinese Vesion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/D3LToolenWin732bit.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite 1.0 (4/27/2018) for 32-bit Windows 7，8，10 Chinese Vesion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-in-chinese&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog(in Chinese)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/2018/05/18/MODIS%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E7%9A%84%E7%AE%80%E4%BB%8B%E5%92%8C%E4%B8%8B%E8%BD%BD%EF%BC%88%E5%85%AD%EF%BC%89%E2%80%94%E2%80%94%E5%9F%BA%E4%BA%8E%E6%B5%8F%E8%A7%88%E5%99%A8%E6%A8%A1%E6%8B%9F%E7%99%BB%E9%99%86%E4%B8%8B%E8%BD%BD%E7%9A%84%E6%96%B9%E5%BC%8F%E4%BB%A5%E5%8F%8AD3L%20Tool%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MODIS数据的简介和下载（六）——基于浏览器模拟登陆下载的方式以及D3L Tool开发&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-website&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/D3LTool/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D3L Tool of NASA Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical Detector in R</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/geographical-detector-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/geographical-detector-in-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Due to the limitation of Excel software of geographical detector, I developed the Geographical Detector by R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geodetector.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Geographical Detector Offical Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/%E7%A9%BA%E9%97%B4%E7%BB%9F%E8%AE%A1%E7%90%86%E8%AE%BA%E5%9B%BE%EF%BC%88%E7%8E%8B%E5%8A%B2%E5%B3%B0%EF%BC%89.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-detailed-information&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Detailed Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are fulfilling the information and software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scale Effect, Zoning Effect of Geographical Features, the Modified Areal Unit Problem and the Chanlleges of Spatial Stastistics</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2018-05-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2018-05-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scale effect and zoning effect are important in geographical research. The combination with scale effect and zoning effect will cause the modified areal unit problem. So how to deal with it in spatial stastics?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Mapping of Direct CO2 Emissions and Uncertainties at the Urban Scale </title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2018-05-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 16:15:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2018-05-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mapping direct carbon emissions at high-resolution in urban environments could help in the development of measures to mitigate carbon emissions through optimizing the layout of inner structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/SpatialAccuracy2018workshop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/SpatialAccuracy2018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Individual and Interactive Influences of Anthropogenic and Ecological Factors on Forest PM2.5 Concentrations at an Urban Scale</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2018-03-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2018-03-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the effects of different policy tools on China’s emissions reduction innovation(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2018-02-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2018-02-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Research on the effects of command-and-control and market-oriented policy tools on China’s energy conservation and emissions reduction innovation</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-12-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-12-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Landscape-Scale Simulation Analysis of Waterlogging and Sponge City Planning for a Central Urban Area in Fuzhou City, China</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-12-04/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The urban underlying surface heavily influences waterlogging (Arnold and Gibbons 1996). During the urbanization process, vegetation, water, and wetlands are replaced by impervious surfaces, including steel, cement, and other building materials. During the late-1990s, governments began to pay closer attention to the influence of urban underlying surfaces on storm water management. They started to develop low-impact development (LID) practices（Carlson et al 2014; Martin et al 2015; Palla and Genecco 2015）, which seek to use the landscape to control the water source and reduce the shock loads of storm water. Typical LID practices include green roofs, permeable pavements, and other green infrastructures. With the introduction of the Sponge City concept, China has gradually been introducing LID technology to improve the urban underlying surface and the spatial distribution of landscape（Chou 2015）.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most previous research of LID analyzed simulation experiments and storm water management at the small-scale level（Allan et al 1997; Meerow and Newell 2017）, whereas little analysis has been done at the urban level. Moreover, few studies have considered the influence of the natural green infrastructure (NGI), which refers to landscape that is good at receiving water. Here, we analyzed the urban central area of Fuzhou City, China, using remote sensing (RS) and geographic information system (GIS) data to divide the urban underlying surface into NGI and non-NGI landscapes. We extracted the impervious surface from the non-NGI landscape and used the precipitation-volumetric method to simulate waterlogging scenarios. We determined the area of rainwater submersion by simulation experiments, the change in the NGI landscape by overlaying images of the region, and the association between these features by data mining. Using the change in ecology indices, we ascertained the changing spatial patterns of the NGI landscape and used these findings to formulate suggestions for Sponge City planning in Fuzhou. Overall, our work combines three research themes, urban waterlogging, landscape ecology, and data mining, for a deep analysis of the relationship between the NGI landscape and storm runoff in an urban environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flow chart of the study&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/fig2new.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual representation of simulation results for scenario 1 and scenario 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/fig.3%28h%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/fig.3%28i%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the results of this study, we derived the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulation analysis for the central urban area of Fuzhou City, assuming a 100-year storm with rainfall durations of 2 and 4 hours, resulted in submerged depths (areas) of 3.943 m (1.345 km2) and 4.055 m (6.032 km2), to which 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively, were exposed. Submerged areas were found at locations of stronger human activity, which caused a higher risk of waterlogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The area covered by NGI landscape in the central urban area of Fuzhou City decreased considerably and became more fragmented from 2006 to 2014. Urban residential area covers 40% of the converted landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of association rule mining showed that the submerged area has an important relationship with the NGI landscape conversion that, in turn, makes waterlogging frequent in urban areas. We used EIC to measure the change in landscape patterns and spatial distribution of the NGI landscape. Based on the results, we identified some ecological nodes and corridors and made some suggestions related to the Sponge City planning of Fuzhou City.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Effect of Urban Form on PM2.5</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2017-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 11:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2017-11-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We explore the relationship between urban form and PM2.5 based on multi-source data fusion. Our working report won the excellence award in the 5th &amp;ldquo;Share Cup&amp;rdquo; Science and Technology Resources Sharing Service Innovation Competition Competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%AB%E6%9D%AF.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Assement Platform of Urban Forest Ecosystem Servcie Based on InVEST model and IOT</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2017-09-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2017-09-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How the ecology develop in the big data era? We have to combine the landsenses ecology, big data and IOT to solve the environmental problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/tableau.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Research on the Effects of Different Policy Tools on China’s Energy Conservation and Emissions Reduction Innovation Based on the Panel Data of 285 prefectural-level municipalities(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-06-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2017-06-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Criminal Geographical Analysis about Walking Environment of Urban</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2016-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/2016-11-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The urban space environment is an important factor for urban crimes. A greater walkability of city can reduce the crime rate in many Criminal Geography theories. However, there is few empirical studies in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://p04n283nf.bkt.clouddn.com/03551963773.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simulation Analysis of Waterlogging and the Sponge City Planning Control of Central Urabn Area in Fuzhou City</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2016-06-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2016-06-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Analysis of Urban Spatial Development Pattern in Beijing Based on the Big Data of Government(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2016-06-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/2016-06-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
