<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guibin Jiang | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/guibin-jiang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/guibin-jiang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Guibin Jiang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2024 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Guibin Jiang</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/guibin-jiang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of two-dimensional copper signatures in human blood for bladder cancer with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cs-corrplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cs-corrplot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pubs.rsc.org/image/article/2022/SC/d1sc06156a/d1sc06156a-f2_hi-res.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1.  Cu concentration and the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients grouped by cancer grade, cancer stage, age, and gender. Each symbol presents an individual subject. (A and B) Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different grades. “Low” refers to low-grade BCa (n = 16) and “high” refers to high-grade BCa (n = 21). PA = 0.7910 and PB = 0.8324, Mann Whitney test. (C and D) δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different grades. PC = 0.0227 and PD = 0.1854, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (E and F) Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different cancer stages (n = 31 for Ta/T1 and n = 4 for T2/T3). PE = 0.9692 and PF = 0.7699, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (G and H) δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different cancer stages. PG = 0.2094 and PH = 0.5604, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (I and J) Variation of the Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of all subjects with age. (K and L) Variation of the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with age. (M and N) Variation of the Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with gender (n = 28 for male and n = 13 for female). PM = 0.1083, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test; PN = 0.2924, Mann Whitney test. (O and P) Variation of the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with gender. PO = 0.8701 and PP = 0.7349, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
