<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yin Ren | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/yin-ren/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/yin-ren/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yin Ren</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2025 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Yin Ren</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/yin-ren/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local carbon emission zone construction in the highly urbanized regions: Application of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in Shanghai, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S036013232301034X-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The flowchart of the LCEZ construction. Step 1: Luojia1-01 night light image data is the proxy variable of the RTCE map. GWR is geographically weighted regression. Step 2: L is low. M is medium. H is high. the solid line is the three key factors. The dotted line means that n key factors can be selected in the future. The point is POI. the column is BF. the line is RD. A&amp;amp;B represents Dense&amp;amp;sparse forests. C&amp;amp;D represents Farmland&amp;amp;grassland&amp;amp;wetland. G represents the water body.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A predition method of subtropical forest biomass</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the accuracy of forest biomass estimate using source analysis and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A biomass estimation method by fusing plot data and forest inventory data</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of the functional mixed entropy for the explanation of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in the urban center of China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.iue.cas.cn/xwzx/kydt/202211/W020221125307842798054.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 The relation between the functional mixed entropy and the GWR mean regression coefficients in 31 cities. The red, yellow, light blue and blue dot represents the Type Ⅰ, Ⅱ, Ⅲ and Ⅳ city, respectively. The numbers follow the city names represent the size order of the urban area. Point A, B and C are hypothetical.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Plot-Level Model of Forest Biomass: A Combined Approach Using Machine Learning with Spatial Statistics</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g002-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Framework for estimating (a–c) the machine learning models, (d) the P-BSHADE model, and the three models that combine machine learning with the P-BSHADE model ((a,d), (b,d) and (c,d)).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g004-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Prediction performance of the seven different models. (a) MAE and (b) MRE are presented as boxplots for each prediction method, with the median (black horizontal line in the box), interquartile range (25–75% in the box), range 5–95% (whiskers), and outliers (asterisks) labeled (S1 = SVM, S2 = RBF-ANN, S3 = RF, S4 = P-BSHADE, S5 = SVM &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S6 = RBF-ANN &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S7 = RF &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S8 = allometric model, Allome = allometric model, ML = machine learning, and Sp Stats = spatial statistics). Histogram distributions of RMSE and nRMSE for each prediction method are presented in panels &amp;copy; and (d), respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g005-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 Improved accuracy assessment indexes of three combined machine learning and spatial statistical methods are revealed by comparison with three corresponding machine learning methods. Panels (a–d) show the MAE, MRE, RMSE, and nRMSE, respectively; S1 vs. S5 compares S5 with S1, S2 vs. S6 compares S6 with S2, and S3 vs. S7 compares S7 with S3 (S1 = SVM, S2 = RBF-ANN, S3 = RF, S5 = SVM &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S6 = RBF-ANN &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S7 = RF &amp;amp; P-BSHADE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forest AGB estimates at the plot level play a major role in connecting accurate single-tree AGB measurements to relatively difficult regional AGB estimates. However, AGB estimates at the plot level are plagued by numerous uncertainties. Improving the plot-level model of forest AGB is a key issue in producing accurate AGB maps. A variety of prediction models have been applied to make accurate AGB estimates, all of which have their own advantages and disadvantages. Different approaches complement the advantages of different models and may yield more accurate AGB estimates than would otherwise be produced by using a single method. The main goal of the current study was to determine whether combining machine learning with spatial statistics can improve plot-level AGB estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study explores the prediction performance of different AGB models, and the results show that the model combining the random forest and P-BSHADE models substantially improves the accuracy of the estimates of forest AGB. The results of this study suggest that combining machine learning with spatial statistics improves plot-level AGB estimates. The understanding gained here should help to improve AGB mapping in other regions and in different types of forests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refined water security assessment for sustainable water management: A case study of 15 key cities in the Yangtze River Delta, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jem-water-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jem-water-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars-els-cdn-com.ezproxy2.utwente.nl/content/image/1-s2.0-S0301479721006502-ga1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The direct and interactive impacts of hydrological factors on bacillary dysentery across different geographical regions in central China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ste-impact-hydrological-factors-bacillary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ste-impact-hydrological-factors-bacillary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0048969720381407-ga1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0048969720381407-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The conceptual diagram illustrating the relationship between bacillary dysentery and hydrological factors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Uncertainties Propagation Analysis of CO$_2$ Emissions Gridded Maps at the Urban Scale: A Case Study of Jinjiang City, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/uncertainty-propogation-co2-map-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/uncertainty-propogation-co2-map-rs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphical-abstract&#34;&gt;Graphical abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-ag-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A proposed workflow to analyze the uncertainties caused by gridded model and model input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine-resolution (30 m) maps have a larger spatial variation in CO$_2$ emissions, which gives the fine-resolution maps a higher degree of uncertainty propagation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This indicates a nonlinear change between the sum of the uncertainties for different sectors and the actual uncertainties in the gridded maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nonlinear change can be explained by the “compensation of error” phenomenon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estimating $CO_2$ emissions at the urban scale, including both un-gridded (i.e., administrative unit maps) and gridded maps, cannot avoid the propagation of uncertainties from input to result, which highlights the importance of being aware of uncertainty estimation, especially in gridded maps due to its implications for the precision mitigation of $CO_2$ emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the above mentioned issue, an analytic workflow was proposed to analyze the propagated uncertainties caused by the gridded model and the input for gridded $CO_2$ emission maps. The present workflow used four sub-modules based on Monte Carlo simulations and a bootstrap sampling method to analyze uncertainties, without other detailed open emission inventories. Two of the submodules obtained the corresponding uncertainty of each grid value, generated the uncertainty map caused by the gridded model, and the uncertainties for the sum of each cell (also referred to as propagated uncertainties caused by the model); the other submodules generated the uncertainty distribution maps based on the total emission estimations and spatial proxies (also referred to as propagated uncertainties caused by input).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g001-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytic workflow of the uncertainty propagation in gridded $CO_2$ emission maps. ALs, activity levels; CI, confidence interval; EFs, emission factors; GDP, gross domestic product; KS, Kolmogorov–Smirnov; LUT, look up table; MLE, maximum likelihood estimation; NTL, night time light; PDFs, probability distribution functions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We regarded the gridded maps of $CO_2$ emissions constructed in previous studies as a case study, and applied the workflow to estimate the uncertainties. The estimation of different uncertainties helps decision makers in formulating relevant policies. Uncertainties in total emission estimations aid the determination of emission reduction targets, the corresponding risks for cities and enterprises, and significant emission sources. Uncertainty maps could help to identify locations suitable for developing low-carbon communities. Fine-resolution (30 m) maps have a larger spatial variation in $CO_2$ emissions, which gives the fine-resolution maps a higher degree of uncertainty propagation. Furthermore, the uncertainties of gridded $CO_2$ emission maps, caused by inserting a random error into spatial proxies, were found to decrease after the gridding process. This can be explained by the “compensation of error” phenomenon, which may be attributed to the cancellation of the overestimated and underestimated values among the different sectors at the same grid. This indicates a nonlinear change between the sum of the uncertainties for different sectors and the actual uncertainties in the gridded maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u1&#34;&gt;U1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g004-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2  CDF curve of different $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolution. The upper figures are at 30 m resolution, while the lower figures are at 500 m resolution. The red line is the distribution of the real values, while the blue line is the distribution of the simulated values. (a,e) are the total $CO_2$ emissions, (b,f) are the residential $CO_2$ emissions, (c,g) are the industrial $CO_2$ emissions, and (d,h) are the transport $CO_2$ emissions. KS., Kolmogorov–Smirnov; Sd, Standard deviation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g005-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3  Uncertainty maps made by the gridded model of $CO_2$ emissions in Jinjiang city, at resolutions of 30 m (a–d) and 500 m (e–h). (a,e) show uncertainty maps of total $CO_2$ emissions. (b,f) show uncertainty maps of residential $CO_2$ emissions. (c,g) show uncertainty maps of industrial $CO_2$ emissions. (d,h) show uncertainty maps of transport $CO_2$ emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u2&#34;&gt;U2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g006-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 $CO_2$ emission population (statistic term) distributions of different sectors. The left figures are at 30 m resolution, while the right figures are at 500 m resolution. The red line is the distribution of the real values, and the blue line is the distribution of the simulated values. (a,e) are the total $CO_2$ emissions, (b,f) are the residential $CO_2$ emissions, (c,g) are the industrial $CO_2$ emissions, and (d,h) are the transport $CO_2$ emission.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u3&#34;&gt;U3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g007-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5 Map showing the uncertainty caused by activity levels. (a,b) represent the uncertainty maps of total $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolution, respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u4&#34;&gt;U4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g008-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6 Maps of uncertainty caused by the spatial proxies. (a,b) represent the maps of uncertainty of total $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A spatial database of CO$_2$ emissions, urban form fragmentation and city-scale effect related impact factors for the low carbon urban system in Jinjiang city, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-dib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-dib/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More fragmentized urban form more CO$_2$ emissions? A comprehensive relationship from the combination analysis across different scales</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/relationship-co2-fragmentation-jclp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/relationship-co2-fragmentation-jclp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of multi-source data and an analytical framework composed of 3 methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration of the impact of 30-m versus 500-m spatial resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low fragmented mixed and industrial lands affect CO$_2$ emissions negatively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low fragmented residential and public lands affect CO$_2$ emissions positively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactions of factors are weaker at a 30-m resolution than at a 500-m resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the industrial production, transportation, local weather, and fossil fuel use, urban form is the factor that affects energy-related CO$_2$ emissions from human activities secondarily. The major forms of human activity affected by urban form are traffic and residential energy consumption/use emissions. After a wide examination of the relationship between urban higher fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions, scholars found fragmentation of land use areas (i.e. areas designated for human activities or purposes) is associated with greater CO$_2$ emissions. However, the evidences might be biased by the uncertainties from the spatial distribution of emissions (also referred to “downscaling”, or “representation” uncertainty), the delineation of urban fragmentation landscape, and the analysis method, which ignores the spatial heterogeneity. Zuo et al. (2019) published the study in the Journal of Cleaner Production, which compared the relationships between urban form fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions in an urban system through the analytic framework composed of the Pearson correlation analysis, geographically weighted regression (GWR), and geographical detector methods with the use of multi-source data to construct the CO$_2$ emissions maps. The analytical framework can be applied to CO$_2$ emissions research in urban agglomerations, megacities, and small towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/JCLP/JCLP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytical Framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the GWR analysis, the coarse resolution resulted in: 1) positive coefficients of fragmentation metric becoming negative, and 2) greater absolute values of negative coefficients. As to the results of Geographical detector, single factor impact powers and interactions among fragmentation factors showed a weakening effect at R$_{30m}$, but a strengthening and weakening effect at R500m. However, there were common results observed in low-fragmented areas across different scales. That is, in low-fragmented mixed-function areas and industrial areas, the more fragmented the area was, the less the CO2 emission there would be. However, in low-fragmented residential, administrative and public service areas, the more fragmented the area was, the higher the CO$_2$ emission there would be. Therefore, the government should disperse the mixed function zones and industrial parcels with diverse types of land, and build the contiguous residential and public service land in the low fragmentation area of urban system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/JCLP/fig6new.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Geographical detector results for fragmentation factors, PUA, and POID for CO$_2$ emissions from 4 sources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Scale effect” has always been the hot topic in landscape ecology research. Although, there are many studies on the driving force of urban environmental problems by using landscape metrics. Most studies are carried out in regional, continental and global scales. However, in this study, we explored the relationship between the urban form fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions in the city scale from the perspective of dual resolution sizes and summarized the research conclusions that can be used in urban internal management based on the analysis results of small towns. At the same time, the influence of scale effect and how to choose the appropriate scale were discussed in the discussion section. The rigorous discussion was also made on whether the research conclusion is applicable to medium and large cities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impacts of climate and land use/land cover changes on water yield service in Ningbo region(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lucc-invest-water-yield/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lucc-invest-water-yield/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining the Mechanisms that Influence the Surface Temperature of Urban Forest Canopies by Combining Remote Sensing Methods, Ground Observations, and Spatial Statistical Models</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lst-geodector-satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lst-geodector-satellite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Heavy Metal Sources in the Soil of Riverbanks Across an Urbanization Gradient</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/heavy-metal-geodetector/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/heavy-metal-geodetector/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Walking Environment on Robbery, Snatch and Theft Crime in Urban Area, H City, China(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;scientific-problems&#34;&gt;Scientific problems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) The influence of urban walking environment on the RST, whether it is in consitent with the theory of good urban walking environment and reducing crime rate in western context?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) What are the characteristics and laws of urban walking environment on RST?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/201812052312.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytic framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180601.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Walking environment in urban&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180602.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 The results of spatial aggregation(a) and spatial autocorrelation(b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180603.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The spatial distribution of residence probability of suspects under the different distances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180604.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5 The visualization of correlation coefficient matrix and scatter plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180605.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6 Spatial variation of regression coefficient of GWGLM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed that the walking environment probably has a positive effect on the RST crime in H city, the greater walkability, the more RST. The effects of walking environment probably has spatial heterogeneity features both on RST and the residence probability of suspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wechat-articles&#34;&gt;Wechat articles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/4AOmOlRPz--PQpRbgdiXqw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;【犯罪地理专栏】H市城区步行环境对两抢一盗警情的影响&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the prediction accuracy of forest aboveground biomass benchmark map by integrating machine learning and spatial statistics</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution mapping of direct CO$_2$ emissions and uncertainties at the urban scale</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-ei-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-ei-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual and Interactive Influences of Anthropogenic and Ecological Factors on Forest PM2.5 Concentrations at an Urban Scale</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-geodetector-multi-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-geodetector-multi-factors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape-Scale Simulation Analysis of Waterlogging and Sponge City Planning for a Central Urban Area in Fuzhou City, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscape-blue-green-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscape-blue-green-space/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The urban underlying surface heavily influences waterlogging. During the urbanization process, vegetation, water, and wetlands are replaced by impervious surfaces, including steel, cement, and other building materials. During the late-1990s, governments began to pay closer attention to the influence of urban underlying surfaces on storm water management. They started to develop low-impact development (LID) practices, which seek to use the landscape to control the water source and reduce the shock loads of storm water. Typical LID practices include green roofs, permeable pavements, and other green infrastructures. With the introduction of the Sponge City concept, China has gradually been introducing LID technology to improve the urban underlying surface and the spatial distribution of landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most previous research of LID analyzed simulation experiments and storm water management at the small-scale level, whereas little analysis has been done at the urban level. Moreover, few studies have considered the influence of the natural green infrastructure (NGI), which refers to landscape that is good at receiving water. Here, we analyzed the urban central area of Fuzhou City, China, using remote sensing (RS) and geographic information system (GIS) data to divide the urban underlying surface into NGI and non-NGI landscapes. We extracted the impervious surface from the non-NGI landscape and used the precipitation-volumetric method to simulate waterlogging scenarios. We determined the area of rainwater submersion by simulation experiments, the change in the NGI landscape by overlaying images of the region, and the association between these features by data mining. Using the change in ecology indices, we ascertained the changing spatial patterns of the NGI landscape and used these findings to formulate suggestions for Sponge City planning in Fuzhou. Overall, our work combines three research themes, urban waterlogging, landscape ecology, and data mining, for a deep analysis of the relationship between the NGI landscape and storm runoff in an urban environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig2new.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Flow chart of the study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submerged areas were characterized by high population densities and high levels of human activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1 Simulation results of storm water scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Simulated parameter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Storm intensity($L·S^{-1}·ha^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;163.183&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101.847&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runoff($L·S^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.342×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.668×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maximum submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged area ($km^{2}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.345&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.032&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main submerged area in Fuzhou included the central business district. Numbers of people exposed to the submerged areas of scenarios 1 and 2 were 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28h%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28i%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Visual representation of simulation results for scenario 1 and scenario 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatial association rule mining revealed a strong association between areas that were converted from NGI landscape and areas that were submerged in our simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 2  Results of association rule mining&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rules&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Confidence&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lift&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged=&amp;gt;Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.655&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stay=&amp;gt;No Submerged&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.865&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an area was submerged, then the probability that the area was converted landscape was 21.2%. If an area was not subject to landscape conversion, then the probability that it would not be a submerged area was 99.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the results of this study, we derived the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulation analysis for the central urban area of Fuzhou City, assuming a 100-year storm with rainfall durations of 2 and 4 hours, resulted in submerged depths (areas) of 3.943 m (1.345 km2) and 4.055 m (6.032 km2), to which 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively, were exposed. Submerged areas were found at locations of stronger human activity, which caused a higher risk of waterlogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The area covered by NGI landscape in the central urban area of Fuzhou City decreased considerably and became more fragmented from 2006 to 2014. Urban residential area covers 40% of the converted landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of association rule mining showed that the submerged area has an important relationship with the NGI landscape conversion that, in turn, makes waterlogging frequent in urban areas. We used EIC to measure the change in landscape patterns and spatial distribution of the NGI landscape. Based on the results, we identified some ecological nodes and corridors and made some suggestions related to the Sponge City planning of Fuzhou City.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Effect of Urban Form on PM2.5: A Case Study of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Urban Agglomerations(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25-leworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25-leworkshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
