<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/tags/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2019 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the prediction accuracy of forest aboveground biomass benchmark map by integrating machine learning and spatial statistics</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Effect of Urban Form on PM2.5, A Case Study of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Urban Agglomeration</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/iale2017talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/talk/iale2017talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We explore the relationship between urban form and PM2.5 based on multi-source data fusion. Our working report won the excellence award in the 5th &amp;ldquo;Share Cup&amp;rdquo; Science and Technology Resources Sharing Service Innovation Competition Competition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Effect of Urban Form on PM2.5: A Case Study of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Urban Agglomerations(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Pollution Map</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/air-pollution-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/air-pollution-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.mdpi.com/atmosphere/atmosphere-10-00055/article_deploy/html/images/atmosphere-10-00055-g004-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1 The spatial distribution of changes in annual average PM2.5 concentrations in different YRD cities from 2005 to 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proportion of level V concentrations continuously increased from 0.00% in 2005 to 7.75% in 2015, showing a rapid expansion trend in the YRD. The proportion of level I and level V concentration gradually increased from 2005 to 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.mdpi.com/atmosphere/atmosphere-10-00055/article_deploy/html/images/atmosphere-10-00055-g007-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2 Annual average PM2.5 concentrations in different climate, ecosystem and geomorphological subregions (NS = North subtropical humid zone, CS = Central subtropical humid zone, AL = Arable land ecosystem, FL=Forest ecosystem, GL = Grassland ecosystem, WL = Water and wetland ecosystem, HS = Human settlement ecosystem, PL = Plain, TL = Tableland, HI = Hills, Mo1 = Small-undulating mountain, Mo2 = Mid-undulating mountain, Mo3 = Large-undulating mountain)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the years 2005, 2010 and 2015, average PM2.5 concentrations were highest in the subregion of the human settlement ecosystem , followed by the farmland ecosystem  and the wetland ecosystem . Average PM2.5 concentrations were highest in the north subtropic humid climate subregion and the central subtropic humid climate subregion . And finally, average PM2.5 concentrations were highest in the geomorphological plain subregion, followed by the platform subregion and the hilly subregion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-10-00521/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-10-00521-g002-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3 Spatial distributions of urban forest PM2.5 concentrations on three different days at the optimal distance threshold of 3500 m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spatial distributions of PM2.5 concentrations on 13 and 29 December 2014 and 14 January 2015 showed significant spatial clustering. The aggregated areas (hot spots and cold spots) of PM2.5 identified by Getis-Ord Gi* showed that PM2.5 hot spots were concentrated in urban centers and suburbs and cold spots were mainly distributed in the suburbs and exurban regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-10-00521/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-10-00521-g005-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figrue 4 Scores for the interactive effects of impact factors sensitivity rankings at the three periods studied calculated based on simulations using multisource data (A is the result on 13 December 2014; B is the result on 29 December 2014; C is the result on 14 January 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the acceleration of urbanization, the interactive effects of population density, impervious surface percentage, and other factors could result in increased air pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-Temporal GIS Theory</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spatial-temporal data is the key to handling big data in this era. Therefore, we need to explored and improved the spatial-temporal GIS theory. On the other hand, we could used the big data to study the traditional spatial-temporal GIS theory and its applicathions such as spatial-temporal human behaviour, criminal geographical theory. Furthermore, scale effect and the modified areal unit problem(MAUP) are also the unsolved problems in geographical study. We want to improve the spatial-temporal geographical theory and its applicathions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Blue and Green Space</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/urban-blue-and-green-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/urban-blue-and-green-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the new normal period of economic transition in China, The Government came up with the concept of the Sponge City, we have some different views of sponge city planning
The research extracted the impervious surface from the non-NGI(natural green infrastructure ) landscape and used the precipitation-volumetric method to simulate waterlogging scenarios. We determined the area of rainwater submersion by simulation experiments, the change in the NGI landscape by overlaying images of the region, and the association between these features by data mining. Using the change in ecology indices, we ascertained the changing spatial patterns of the NGI landscape and used these findings to formulate suggestions for Sponge City planning in Fuzhou. Overall, our work combines three research themes, urban waterlogging, landscape ecology, and data mining, for a deep analysis of the relationship between the NGI landscape and storm runoff in an urban environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submerged areas were characterized by high population densities and high levels of human activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 1 Simulation results of storm water scenarios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Simulated parameter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Storm intensity($L·S^{-1}·ha^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;163.183&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101.847&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runoff($L·S^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.342×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.668×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maximum submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged area ($km^{2}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.345&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.032&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main submerged area in Fuzhou included the central business district. Numbers of people exposed to the submerged areas of scenarios 1 and 2 were 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28h%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28i%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2 Visual representation of simulation results for scenario 1 and scenario 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatial association rule mining revealed a strong association between areas that were converted from NGI landscape and areas that were submerged in our simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 2 Results of association rule mining&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rules&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Confidence&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lift&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged=&amp;gt;Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.655&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stay=&amp;gt;No Submerged&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.865&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an area was submerged, then the probability that the area was converted landscape was 21.2%. If an area was not subject to landscape conversion, then the probability that it would not be a submerged area was 99.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we used multi-source data to identify the urban ecological-production-living spaces and provided some suggesstions for urban resilience simulation optimization. We developed some ArcGIS toolbox based on model builder and Python. Our results won the national third prize in the 2th big data supports spatial plannning and design competition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Carbon Cycle</title>
      <link>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/urban-carbon-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://giserdaishaoqing.github.io/mycv/project/urban-carbon-cycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we propose herein a low-cost method that combines machine learning and spatial statistics to construct a regional biomass map from non-representative sample units. Secondly, we scaled up an ecological process model to obtain the spatial distribution of regional biomass. Finally, we used some data assimilation technology by these data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/figcs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure The accuracy of different methods for biomass estimation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities are the main sources of $CO_2$ emissions and, thus, must abate emissions responsibly. About 50% of urban $CO_2$ emissions was attributed to urban forms, mixed land use, building types, and transportation networks.  It is necessary to characterize the pixel-based distribution of urban direct $CO_2$ emissions accurately. But large uncertainties was found at the urban scale, it&amp;rsquo;s important to analyze the uncertainties of $CO_2$ emissions gridded map at the urban scale. Besides, exlporing the relationship between $CO_2$ emissions and urban form is useful for planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/contribution.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2 Comparison between our high resolution $CO_2$ emission gridding map and CHRED&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;detailed informations can see &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/CEopendata.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We compared the relationships between urban form fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions in an urban system through the analytic framework composed of the Pearson correlation analysis, geographically weighted regression (GWR), and geographical detector methods with the use of multi-source data to construct the CO$_2$ emissions maps. The analytical framework can be applied to CO$_2$ emissions research in urban agglomerations, megacities, and small towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/JCLP/JCLP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3 Analytical Framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
