<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chunxing Li | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/chunxing-li/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/chunxing-li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Chunxing Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2025 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Chunxing Li</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/authors/chunxing-li/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response of syntrophic bacterial and methanogenic archaeal communities in paddy soil to soil type and phenological period of rice growth</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-responserice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-responserice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652620334636-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Distributions of syntrophs (SPOB and SBOB) and methanogens in the 10 paddy soils (a) at different rice growth stages (b).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652620334636-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Environmental drivers of syntrophic bacteria composition in the 10 paddy soils (a) at different rice growth stages (b). Pairwise comparisons of environmental parameters and bacterial communities are demonstrated, and the color gradient indicates Spearman’s correlation coefficients. Total syntrophs and SFAS were correlated to each environmental factor, as revealed by the partial Mantel tests. The edge color and width represent the statistical significance and Mantel’s R statistic, respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of high-ash industrial sludge for producing improved char with low heavy metal toxicity</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jaap-corrplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jaap-corrplot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0165237020303223-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Pearson correlation between heavy metal speciation and characteristics of industrial sludge and char samples: (a) F1 + F2 fractions; (b) F3 fraction; &amp;copy; F4 fraction. The color (red to blue) indicates the change in correlation from negative to positive and the size of bubble shows the strength of correlation, which can be expressed by skew-symmetric numbers. Cross shows non-significant correlation between heavy metal and char property (P &amp;gt;  0.05). SA presents BET specific surface area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
