<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spatial-Temporal GIS Theory | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/tags/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/tags/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spatial-Temporal GIS Theory</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2023 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Spatial-Temporal GIS Theory</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/tags/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local carbon emission zone construction in the highly urbanized regions: Application of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in Shanghai, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S036013232301034X-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The flowchart of the LCEZ construction. Step 1: Luojia1-01 night light image data is the proxy variable of the RTCE map. GWR is geographically weighted regression. Step 2: L is low. M is medium. H is high. the solid line is the three key factors. The dotted line means that n key factors can be selected in the future. The point is POI. the column is BF. the line is RD. A&amp;amp;B represents Dense&amp;amp;sparse forests. C&amp;amp;D represents Farmland&amp;amp;grassland&amp;amp;wetland. G represents the water body.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing spatiotemporal bikeability using multi-source geospatial big data: A case study of Xiamen, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jag-bikeability-multisource/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jag-bikeability-multisource/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposed-bikeability-framework&#34;&gt;Proposed bikeability framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We construct the bikeability evaluation framework by combining the collected multi-source spatio-temporal big data (Figure 1 and Figure 2). The proposed bikeability evaluation framework contains four subindexes, i.e., safety, comfort, accessibility, and vitality, and thirteen influencing indicators, i.e., wind speed, road slope, precipitation, temperature, sky view index, green view index, trajectory sinuosity, air pollution, average speed of trajectory, public transportation accessibility, commercial accessibility, number of trajectory and crowdedness. All indicators used in our framework belong to objective and quantitative measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The proposed bikeability framework.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Street view imagery semantic segmentation process, revised from Chen et al. (2018).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spatiotemporal-analysis-of-bikeability&#34;&gt;Spatiotemporal analysis of bikeability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first present and discuss the results of four subindexes across Xiamen Island on a daily basis from December 21 to 25th, 2020 (Figure 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. The figures show the daily safety, comfort, accessibility, and vitality of Xiamen Island from top row to bottom row, where from left column to right column respectively represent the dates from 21 to 25th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calculation of the bikeability index requires assigning appropriate weights to each indicators. To determine these weights, we performed a principal component analysis (PCA) on the 13 indicators. The PCA resulted in 6 components, providing a balance between a minimal number of components and reliable explained variance. The relationships between components and indicators are displayed in Figure 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4. The PCA result for 13 indicators indicates correspondence between principal components and original indicators.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temporal distribution of the bikeability index shows a fluctuation throughout the study period, as seen in Figure 5.The temporal distribution of the bikeability index shows a fluctuation throughout the study period, as seen in Fig. 8. On the 21st and 22nd, the average values were recorded as 0.236 and 0.233, respectively. On the 23rd, however, there was a noticeable drop in the bikeability index value, reaching a low of 0.098. Despite this decrease, the values rebounded to 0.188 and 0.185 on the 24th and 25th, respectively. This fluctuation in the bikeability index is mainly due to a rainfall event that occurred in Xiamen on the 23rd. The rainy conditions led to a significant decrease in the safety subindex, which in turn decreased the overall value of the bikeability index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island on December 21st, 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 2020, the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hourly pattern of the bikeability index reveals a different trend compared to the daily change (Fig. 8). As seen in Fig. 8, the hourly bikeability index values exhibit much less fluctuation. The value was recorded as 0.184 at 6:00 a.m. and then gradually increased, reaching its peak at 7:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m. with values of 0.198 and 0.195, respectively. This increase was mainly due to an increase in the vitality subindex, as more people were using shared bicycles between 7:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m. on working days. However, at 9:00 a.m., the value dropped to its lowest point at 0.17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island at 6:00, 7:00, 8:00, and 9:00 a.m., the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further validate our proposed index, we conducted a case study analysis in the central area of Xiamen CR, which is the middle continuous hotspot area. The location of this case study is the shared bicycle cycling hotspot at the intersection of Hubin Nanlu and Hubin Donglu, near the commercial center of Xiamen Wanxiangcheng, between 8:00–9:00 a.m. on December 21, 2020, as shown in Figure 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 7. Case study field validation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study area is centered around the Huarun commercial center, surrounded by a large residential area. During the morning hours, a substantial amount of shared bicycles are used in this region, contributing to a relatively high bikeability index. This highlights the significance of cycling routes in determining the level of bikeability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current cycling infrastructure falls short of supporting high-friendly cycling routes. For example, the road section near Hubin Middle School, which is located in a residential area and has a high demand for commuting, features a high density of shared bicycle stops, catering, shopping, and life services. The natural environment also favors cycling with low slopes, moderate wind speed, low precipitation, suitable temperature, overcast weather, and good air quality. Despite these favorable conditions, this section is congested during the morning rush hour due to a narrow non-motorized lane, slow average speed, and high volume of people commuting and going to school, resulting in low bikeability in this section despite high cycling activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the demand for shared bicycles in hot spot regions is much higher, underscoring the importance of ensuring the availability of bicycles and easy accessibility. As shown in the figure, most road sections in the hot spot area have high densities of parking spots. However, there is a shortage of parking spots on the east side of Huarun Center, leading to a concentration of cyclists in other areas, causing congestion and potentially affecting commuting efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case study showcases how our bikeability index takes into account the purpose of cycling and reflects cyclists’ preferred routes. Nonetheless, there remain disparities between the actual infrastructure, preferred routes, and regional conditions. By integrating the index system with real-time data, it is possible to provide suggestions for enhancing regional cycling conditions. The findings of this research can guide management departments and shared bicycle providers to improve facilities and offer optimal route planning for cyclists to avoid congestion and overcome difficulties in finding available bicycles. In conclusion, the bikeability index can provide comprehensive decision-making recommendations and advance the development of cycling-friendly cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;implications-for-policy-and-practice&#34;&gt;Implications for policy and practice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The variability in the bikeability index across different segments presents an opportunity for transportation planners to enhance cycling infrastructure. Monitoring the spatiotemporal dynamics of bikeability can help identify potential environmental or infrastructure changes and their impact on the community’s level of bikeability. To ensure the relevance of the cycling friendliness index, case studies that incorporate additional infrastructure data are necessary for local comparison of bikeability results, enabling the proposal of landable solutions for varying infrastructure. For instance, the fusion analysis of parking spot electronic fence data and bikeability could expose discrepancies between regional cycling infrastructure and cyclists’ preferences, providing actionable recommendations to government departments and guiding users to cycle in a more bike-friendly manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking your interest and going ahead will contribute to success</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/xmno12023talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/xmno12023talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of the functional mixed entropy for the explanation of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in the urban center of China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.iue.cas.cn/xwzx/kydt/202211/W020221125307842798054.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 The relation between the functional mixed entropy and the GWR mean regression coefficients in 31 cities. The red, yellow, light blue and blue dot represents the Type Ⅰ, Ⅱ, Ⅲ and Ⅳ city, respectively. The numbers follow the city names represent the size order of the urban area. Point A, B and C are hypothetical.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do neighborhood boundaries matter for examining the associations between environmental factors and obesity</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/cpgis2022talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/cpgis2022talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying urban mass gain and loss by a GIS-based material stocks and flows analysis</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jie-gisbased-material-stocks-and-flows-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jie-gisbased-material-stocks-and-flows-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/6e2b657e-8240-4c6e-a994-ad0948824e47/jiec13252-fig-0001-m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 A framework combining stock-driven material flow analysis (MFA) and geographical information system (GIS) to simulate material metabolism. This improved framework highlights four typical activities that generate material flows, namely, construction, demolition, replacement, and maintenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High spatial resolution mapping of steel resources accumulated above ground in mainland China: Past trends and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-high-resolution-steels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-high-resolution-steels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652621007022-gr4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Comparisons between predicted and statistics-based steel stocks in 2015 (a), 2016 (b), 2017 (c), and 2018 (d). The gray shading represents 99% confidence intervals of the log-log regression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652621007022-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 National coverage of in-use steel stocks in 2015 at 1 × 1 km grid level and an example (in a partial view) of modelling area (a), and stocks changes during 1995–2015 (b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation of Health Effect of Short-term Exposure to PM2.5 during Spring Festival: A Case Study of 25 Cities in the Yangtze River Delta(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/xu2020talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/xu2020talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We presented the published paper namely &amp;lsquo;The Evaluation of Health Effect of Short-term Exposure to PM2.5 during Spring Festival: A Case Study of 25 Cities in the Yangtze River Delta&amp;rsquo; in &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Urban Planning Review&lt;/em&gt; and discuss the built environment and human health with other participants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation of Health Effect of Short-term Exposure to PM2.5 during Spring Festival: A Case Study of 25 Cities in the Yangtze River Delta(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-health-exposure-shup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-health-exposure-shup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;research-goal&#34;&gt;Research goal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatiotemporal change of health risk of short-term exposure to PM2.5 affected by human mobility during Spring Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Comparison between different machine learning models via spatial cross validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Daily level PM2.5 mapping at 1-km resolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1 The average value and 95% confidence intervals of AF causing by PM2.5 exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;死亡原因&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;$\bar{AF}(+)$(n = 2 858)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;$\bar{AF}(-)$(n = 2 914)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;总死亡&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.28(0.21, 0.33)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.28(0.21, 0.33)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;心血管疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.32(0.24, 0.38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.33(0.25, 0.39)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;高血压疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.19, 0.53)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.41(0.19, 0.54)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;冠心病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.24, 0.41)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.35(0.26, 0.42)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;中风&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.29(0.19, 0.37)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.29(0.19, 0.38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;呼吸道疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.23, 0.42)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.24, 0.43)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;慢性阻塞性肺疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.29, 0.48)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.29, 0.49)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 The changing mode of human mobility-health risk in 25 cities of the Yangtze River Delta during the Spring Festival&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The time variation and OD matrices of AF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should not ignore the health risks of short-term exposure to PM 2.5 caused by human mobility behavior during the Spring Festival, because the estimated average increased risks are from 0.25 to 0.39. The highest risk is more than 0.9. This reveals strong spatiotemporal heterogeneity in the health effect of short-term exposure to PM 2.5. Even the value of risks could change from 0.84 to-0.75 in two days. Most of the travel populations in the Yangtze River Delta have increased the health risk of short-term exposure to PM 2.5 caused by human mobility during the Spring Festival, such as Shanghai and Suzhou, with the exposed populations reaching to nearly 13.2 million and 6 million.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is geography? From coronavirus disease 2019 to Bei Dou Systems</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/ta2020talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/talk/ta2020talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Lifecourse Epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/project/spatial-lifecourse-epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/project/spatial-lifecourse-epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Lifecourse Epidemiology was proposed by my supervisor, Dr.Jia Peng in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanplh/article/PIIS2542-5196(18)30245-6/fulltext&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lancet Planetary Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Now it is also applied to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1471492220300052&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;infectious disease&lt;/a&gt;, especially the COVID-19 pandemic. It&amp;rsquo;s an emerging research field. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://ehp.niehs.nih.gov/doi/full/10.1289/EHP4868&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the top 10 research priorities in Spatial Lifecourse Epidemiology&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1353829219306355&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Spatial Lifecourse Epidemiology Reporting Standards (ISLE-ReSt) statement&lt;/a&gt; publishing in the Journals. My Ph.D. project will focus on how to use the Earth Observation handling(Google Earth Engine), geospatial big data handling(Street View Image segment), and spatial statistics model to explore the health geography and spatial epidemiology problem. Our research interests include obesity, infectious disease like COVID-19, non-communicate disease, but not limited to these topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-obesity&#34;&gt;1 Obesity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We conducted a series of systematic reviews articles in &lt;em&gt;Obesity Reviews&lt;/em&gt; to determine all the obesogenic environmental factors in childhood obesity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/obr.13097&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Natural environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/obr.13100&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Green space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/obr.13042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bike lanes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/obr.13052&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Speed limit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-covid-19-pandemic&#34;&gt;2 COVID-19 Pandemic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-1-covid-19-research-sources&#34;&gt;2.1 COVID-19 research sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built up a website about COVID-19 studies, &lt;a href=&#34;http://covid19.gisersqdai.top/en-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Awesome of COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;. This website was used for collecting all the resources of COVID-19 related studies and was powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/txd-team/docsite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;docsite&lt;/a&gt;. Besides, I developed a dashboard shiny app about COVID-19 map, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gisersqdai.shinyapps.io/COVID19VIS/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COVID-19 shiny app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GISerDaiShaoqing/Awesome_COVID-19/raw/master/img/websnapt.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Snapshot of website &amp;ldquo;Awesome of COVID-19&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GISerDaiShaoqing/Awesome_COVID-19/raw/master/img/quick_start.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Snapshot of COVID-19 shiny app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-2-reverse-of-covid-19&#34;&gt;2.2 Reverse of COVID-19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic can cause reverse zoonoses (i.e., human–animal transmission of COVID-19). It is vital to utilize up-to-date methods to improve the control, management, and prevention of reverse zoonoses. Awareness of reverse zoonoses should be raised at both individual and regional/national levels for better protection of both humans and animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/2021fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Natural Infections of Pet, Zoo, and Livestock Animals as of 11 March 2021 Mapped onto Number of Confirmed Cases in the Human Population.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/Iye21hgtkTlFv95ybRDA0g&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trends论文献策疫情中被忽视的“人-动物”感染风险 | Cell Press论文速递&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-health-effect-of-exposure-to-air-pollution&#34;&gt;3 Health effect of exposure to air pollution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The time variation and OD matrices of AF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/tpBS511WWOWau5jHaneoZg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;【建成环境与行为研究】春节期间的PM2.5污染短期暴露健康效应评估——以长三角地区25个城市为例 | 上海城市规划&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-development-of-spatiotemporal-physical-activity-opportunity-using-multi-source-geospatial-big-data-and-machine-learning&#34;&gt;4 Development of spatiotemporal physical activity opportunity using multi-source geospatial big data and machine learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-1-bikeability&#34;&gt;4.1 Bikeability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We develop a bikeability evaluation framework by combining the collected multi-source spatio-temporal big data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. The proposed bikeability framework.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island on December 21st, 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 2020, the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 7. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island at 6:00, 7:00, 8:00, and 9:00 a.m., the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/lUi7l5uX8DPr1LQgEibjbw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;《Int J Appl Earth Obs》发文：基于多源地理空间大数据的时空自行车可行性评估&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Walking Environment on Robbery, Snatch and Theft Crime in Urban Area, H City, China(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;scientific-problems&#34;&gt;Scientific problems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) The influence of urban walking environment on the RST, whether it is in consitent with the theory of good urban walking environment and reducing crime rate in western context?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) What are the characteristics and laws of urban walking environment on RST?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/201812052312.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytic framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180601.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Walking environment in urban&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180602.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 The results of spatial aggregation(a) and spatial autocorrelation(b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180603.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The spatial distribution of residence probability of suspects under the different distances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180604.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5 The visualization of correlation coefficient matrix and scatter plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180605.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6 Spatial variation of regression coefficient of GWGLM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed that the walking environment probably has a positive effect on the RST crime in H city, the greater walkability, the more RST. The effects of walking environment probably has spatial heterogeneity features both on RST and the residence probability of suspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wechat-articles&#34;&gt;Wechat articles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/4AOmOlRPz--PQpRbgdiXqw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;【犯罪地理专栏】H市城区步行环境对两抢一盗警情的影响&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-Temporal GIS Theory</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/project/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/project/spatial-temporal-gis-theory/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Spatial-temporal data is the key to handling big data in this era. Therefore, we need to explored and improved the spatial-temporal GIS theory. On the other hand, we could used the big data to study the traditional spatial-temporal GIS theory and its applicathions such as spatial-temporal human behaviour, criminal geographical theory. Furthermore, scale effect and the modified areal unit problem(MAUP) are also the unsolved problems in geographical study. We want to improve the spatial-temporal geographical theory and its applicathions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-application-of-spatial-statistical-theory-in-crime-geography&#34;&gt;1 Application of spatial statistical theory in crime geography&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/201812052312.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Analytic framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed that the walking environment probably has a positive effect on the RST crime in H city, the greater walkability, the more RST. The effects of walking environment probably has spatial heterogeneity features both on RST and the residence probability of suspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/4AOmOlRPz--PQpRbgdiXqw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;【犯罪地理专栏】H市城区步行环境对两抢一盗警情的影响&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-development-of-spatiotemporal-mapping-of-urban-elements&#34;&gt;2 Development of spatiotemporal mapping of urban elements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-resolution mapping of steel resources accumulated above ground (referred to as steel stocks) is critical for exploring urban mining and circular economy opportunities. We developed an aggregative downscaling model that fuses multiple large-scale spatial datasets, including gridded population, gross domestic product (GDP), and built-up area. We demonstrated the utility of this model by using it to map steel stocks in mainland China at 1 × 1 km resolution. Our results found the steel stocks increased from 12,873 $t/km^2$ to 33,027 $t/km^2$ during 1995–2015, and four steel stocks clusters (i.e., Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei agglomeration, Yangtze River Delta, Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, and Chengdu-Chongqing metropolitan) possessed over 40% of the national total in 2015, revealing an unbalanced distribution of steel stocks across China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652621007022-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. National coverage of in-use steel stocks in 2015 at 1 × 1 km grid level and an example (in a partial view) of modelling area (a), and stocks changes during 1995–2015 (b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzkyODIzMjAzMg==&amp;amp;mid=2247483767&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=a530f39e1155b29d0bf8b6458deda3dd&amp;amp;chksm=c21aa678f56d2f6e67b241ea75b486fdfcdaee6864f1ffc07ceabbe28ab6d5c3295f6a5035f5&amp;amp;scene=126&amp;amp;sessionid=1689883670#rd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;钢铁城市矿产储量的高精度预测&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-development-of-spatiotemporal-physical-activity-opportunity-using-multi-source-geospatial-big-data-and-machine-learning&#34;&gt;3 Development of spatiotemporal physical activity opportunity using multi-source geospatial big data and machine learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We develop a bikeability evaluation framework by combining the collected multi-source spatio-temporal big data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. The proposed bikeability framework.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island on December 21st, 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 2020, the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island at 6:00, 7:00, 8:00, and 9:00 a.m., the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/lUi7l5uX8DPr1LQgEibjbw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;《Int J Appl Earth Obs》发文：基于多源地理空间大数据的时空自行车可行性评估&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
