<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Shaoqing Dai</title>
    <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2025 Shaoqing Dai</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/site.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built environments and obesity: A framework considering residences, commute routes, and workplaces</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cities-be-obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cities-be-obesity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward 3D hedonic price model for vertically developed cities using street view images and machine learning methods</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/habitati-svi-3dhpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/habitati-svi-3dhpm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-collection&#34;&gt;Data Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workflow of mass-downloading SVIs started with generating the sampling points with an interval of 10 m along the OpenStreetMap (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstreetmap.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.openstreetmap.org&lt;/a&gt;) road networks (Figure 1a). Second, we determined the heading direction and pitch, two parameters in image customisation (Figure 1b and c). Heading direction defines the compass heading of the camera with the value from 0° to 360°. Four heading directions (0°, 90°, 180°, 270°) were selected for a full surrounding view. The pitch represents the up/down angle at which the street view is taken. Compared to other studies that adopt pitch 0° for eye-level only, our strategy incorporates two pitches (0° and 90°) to collect both eye-level images reflecting horizontal streetscape and sky-view images reflecting the vertical sky openness (Figure 1d and e). Finally, we determined the acquisition time: 2019 or 2020. Our objective is to improve the quantity of SVIs by employing a compact sampling point density and a comparatively inclusive acquisition timeframe. Preliminary assessments indicated that not all sampling points have images, and annual updates are not guaranteed. Ideally, if images are available, eight images are collected per year per sampling point. Each image has 1024 ∗ 512 pixels. In total, we generated 83,925 sampling points and downloaded 737,704 images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Distribution of sampling points along the road network, the abstract simulations of eye-level angle  and sky-view angles, and illustrations of SVI in eye-level angle and sky-view angle (a)-(e).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposed-3d-hedonic-price-model&#34;&gt;Proposed 3D hedonic price model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As shown in Figure 2, this study is conducted within the HPM framework, which consists of three steps. We first generate physical, locational variables, extract 3D variables from SVIs, and then construct HPM in different valuation models, namely OLS, GWR and RF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$V=f(P,L,E_{3d})$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. The methodology design and the workflow of 3D hedonic price model (3D HPM).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. The example of semantic segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RF performs the best among all three models. $R^2$ increases from 0.716 to 0.768 by adding 3D variables. In addition to R2 values, RMSE, MAE, and MAPE are also used to evaluate the model accuracy, as shown in Table 3. The lowest RMSE in RF is 1669.60 $yuan/m^2$. Taking the average property value (14,318 $yuan/m^2$), the MAPE of estimation in RF is 11.66%. In summary, OLS has the basic performance, GWR has improvement, and RF has the best explainability and the least errors in different regards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1. The comparison of $R^2$, RMSE, MAE and MAPE among different models (based on group 4). The unit of RMSE and MAE: $yuan/m^2$.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Indicator&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;OLS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GWR&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;RF&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.376&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.636&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.768&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RMSE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3116.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2331.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1669.60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MAE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2199.91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1582.27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1006.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MAPE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 4 gives an overview of 3Dss in GWR. The distribution of 3Dss has a trend of expansion from the centre towards the periphery (Figure 4c and d). The city centre of Xi&amp;rsquo;an has narrow street width and densely distributed buildings. The north and west peripheries have improved urban design with broader roads and more sky exposure. The distribution of its coefficients has a similar tendency (Figure 4a). In the centre, 3Dss has negative values. The fact shows that the presence of sky is not favoured for higher property values. The negativity reduces and eventually becomes positive as it gets farther from the centre. Figure 4b shows the distribution of the p value of 3Dss, indicating the geographical coverage when 3Dss is statistical significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4. The distribution of 3Dss in GWR model: coefficient, p value, variable itsel, and 3D visualisation (a)-(d).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 5 displays the relative importance of all the variables. Among the 3D variables, road, tree and grass from eye-level images are the top three influential variables with values of 1, 0.619 and 0.541. Sky from sky-view images ranks fourth (0.432) in the total and first in sky-view variables. Building from sky-view images closely follows with a value of 0.411. The sequence of other 3D variables is as follows: building (0.369), sky (0.361), sidewalk (0.327) in eye-level images, separately. Tree in sky-view images, has the least value (0.26) among 3D variables, but it is still ahead of several physical and locational variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. The relative importance of variables in Random Forest (RF) model.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 6 illustrates the PDPs of all 3D variables. 3Det, 3Deg, 3Der, 3Dss, and 3Dsb share a similar pattern. In the early stage, there is hardly an impact on property values; then, the influence becomes obvious after a certain value. After reaching another value, the impact again becomes insignificant. Certain values vary among different variables. In eye-level images, tree starts at 0.10 and ends at 0.15; grass starts at 0.08 and ends at 0.22, road starts at 0.23 and ends at 0.26. In sky-view images, sky starts at 0.30 and ends at 0.65, building starts at 0.06 and ends at 0.12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0197397525000049-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6. The partial dependence plots (PDPs) of 3D variables.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the spatial changes happening in the vertical direction in cities because of the construction of high-rise buildings, it is necessary to conceptually and technically identify the hedonic value of 3D and add 3D variables in HPM for property valuation. Our empirical results show: 1) 3D variables have made significant contributions to HPM, and the sky-view angle cannot be overlooked. 2) In the sky-view angle, sky is positively correlated while the presence of buildings and trees are negatively correlated with property values. The influence direction of building and tree are different in eye-level and sky-view images, which further reminds the importance of sky-view angle. 3) RF outperforms OLS and GWR regarding a higher model fitting and stronger explainability power to interpret the influences of 3D variables. The study confirms the important role of 3D in HPM in the context of vertically developed cities with generous amounts of high-rise buildings. Our findings are expected to provide consultancy value for housing policy-making, such as fair property taxation and equal land use policy. In conclusion, this study provides solid evidences that SVIs and AI can quantify the 3D built environment at a low cost on a mass scale (technically feasible), and the sky-view angle is meaningful in valuation practices in vertical cities (practically significant), laying a foundation for future 3D property valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous impacts of and vulnerabilities to the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscapeecology-covid-19-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscapeecology-covid-19-impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving obesogenic environmental assessments with advanced geospatial methods</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/phdthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/phdthesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term exposure to PM2.5 chemical constituents and diabesity: evidence from a multi-center cohort study in China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lanwpc-pm25-diabesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lanwpc-pm25-diabesity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Street view imagery-based built environment auditing tools: a systematic review</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ijgis-bea-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ijgis-bea-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;systematic-review-method&#34;&gt;Systematic review Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the PubMed and Web of Science databases to search for refereed journal articles. To identify articles related to BEA and SVI, we used two sets of search terms: (1) ‘built environment* audit’, ‘auditing’, and ‘virtual audit*’; (2) ‘streetview*’, ‘street view*’, ‘street-view*’, and ‘street view image*’. We collected all the papers published from the inception of the electronic bibliographic databases up to October 2023. We followed the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines to conduct a systematic review (Moher et al. Citation2009), as depicted in Figure 1. Out of 429 initial results, we identified 96 eligible studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/94087bc3-4359-4dbf-9ff6-9548bb3d9935/tgis_a_2336034_f0001_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The flowchart that was followed when selecting and including studies on built environment auditing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;characteristics-of-included-studies&#34;&gt;Characteristics of included studies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All included studies were published after 2010, marking a discernible increase trajectory in the annual number of publications over the past decade, as illustrated in Figure 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/b1f0eb76-d6eb-48ee-9120-110ee2dbd814/tgis_a_2336034_f0002_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Number of the included studies published each year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of the studies (89 of 96, 92.7%) utilized Google SVI for BEA, while the remaining seven studies explored alternative SVI sources including Tencent SVI and Baidu SVI. Additionally, 13 studies employed other SVI sources, such as Bing Map, closed-circuit television, daum road view service, Google Earth, and Google Maps alongside Google SVI. In most studies (78 of 96, 81.3%), SVI was processed for BEA manually. Only 18 studies used computer vision and artificial intelligence technologies. Among these, deep learning techniques were particularly prevalent, employing convolutional neural network models like visual geometry group-16, visual geometry group-19, ResNet-18, SegNet, and DeepLab V3+. These models were specifically tailored for image segmentation tasks, offering fine-scale detection of eye-level objects, such as trees, sidewalks, and bike lanes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEA tools are defined as a range of developed toolsets or instruments utilized to audit and assess built environment attributes, including physical structures, facilities, and surroundings within a given study area, comprising both validated and unvalidated auditing tools. The validated auditing tools were defined as a series of commonly used auditing tools, which are based on well-established references and often implemented as platforms, toolsets, and frameworks. In contrast, unvalidated auditing tools are usually self-developed, lacking validation in other studies, and thus could only serve as conceptual methods without systematic implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/b95b20c6-0fd4-490f-9b14-f4b7dab19fe3/tgis_a_2336034_f0003_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. An overview of the studies using different built environment auditing tools in different countries, (a) represents the number of these tools within different countries (in parentheses), (b) represents the number of these tools that have been applied by different groups and in various studies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/543541e4-3bfc-4421-8302-abdb78417836/tgis_a_2336034_f0004_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4. The number of the included studies using different built environment auditing tools at different scales (in parentheses). Note: N—National; S—State (e.g. in the US) or equivalent unit; C—City; Cn—multicity; County—County or equivalent unit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frequently audited built environment attributes included street-related features (e.g. street lights, street parking, and streetscape aesthetics) (n = 52), sidewalk-related features (e.g. width, buffers, and continuity) (n = 49), and traffic-related features (e.g. signals, volume, public transit stops, and environment) (n = 47). Other notable attributes include land use (n = 33), facility-related features (n = 28), visual perceptions (e.g. aesthetics) (n = 25), and social environment (e.g. safety) (n = 16).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/21f6ad73-3737-4327-8ea9-9d430ee9a217/tgis_a_2336034_f0005_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. The count of studies auditing different built environment attributes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most studies (n = 64), undertook an evaluation of the reliability associated with the assessed built environment attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice of indicators for audited built environment attributes differs among studies. Due to the ambiguity in some auditing characteristic definitions, the reliability and validity of gathered audit measures tend to be higher for objective attributes than subjective assessments. Among audited attributes, the presence of a sidewalk, a typical objective attribute, has the highest average reliability (0.837) across the majority of studies, exceeding the noteworthy threshold of 0.7 (as illustrated in Figure 6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/cms/asset/bcb746f4-5213-4633-a1d3-fd3cb4d72768/tgis_a_2336034_f0006_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6. The average reliability indexes among different built environment attributes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;implications-for-policy-and-practice&#34;&gt;Implications for policy and practice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhancing accuracy in quantifying built environment features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing a suitable SVI-based BEA method and enhancing robustness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressing time lag and spatial limitations of SVI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging the BEA and urban exposome observation through SVI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a systematic review of the commonly audited built environment attributes and auditing tools, our findings provide a comprehensive understanding of the state-of-the-art SVI-based auditing approaches and offer insights into future directions for development. The reliability of these audits varies depending on the type of attribute and the assessment tool used. We have learned that objective attributes, such as the presence of a sidewalk, generally yield higher reliability, while subjective assessments may be influenced by auditor biases, resulting in lower reliability. The use of standardized auditing tools, such as S-VAT, across multiple cities demonstrates the potential for improved comparability and generalizability of research findings. Considering the number of research groups that used these tools, ANC and MAPS were identified as the two most widely accepted auditing tools. Furthermore, many standardized auditing tools have been exclusively implemented in specific countries. This is often attributed to auditing of those attributes that are relevant in these particular countries, which may not necessarily align with conditions found in other nations. Consequently, this localization of attributes has resulted in higher reliability when the tools are applied in the country where they were originally developed, as compared to their performance in other countries. The varying levels of reliability for different attributes within the same tool indicate the need for further refinement and standardization of assessment criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methodology’s merits lie in the adoption of a classification of auditing aims and the integration of various built environment features, ultimately allowing researchers to better understand the relationship between urban design and public health. The broader impact of these findings can inform urban planning and policy-making efforts to promote healthier and more sustainable living environments. Achieving higher reliability in built environment audits requires a careful balance between objective and subjective attributes and the adoption of standardized tools and assessment criteria. This can lead to more robust research findings and an improved understanding of urban environments, ultimately contributing to better-informed urban planning and policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal patterns of air pollutants over the epidemic course: a national study in China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/spatiaotemporal-air-china-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/spatiaotemporal-air-china-rs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of the Art of Lifecourse Cohort Establishment</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lifecourse-cohort-chinacdcweekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lifecourse-cohort-chinacdcweekly/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Dynamic Monitoring and Driving Force Analysis of Eco-Environmental Quality in China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/long-term-ecoquality-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/long-term-ecoquality-rs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed land use has opposite associations with subjective well-being through social capital: Spatial heterogeneity in residential and workplace neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/tbs-mixed-land-use-well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/tbs-mixed-land-use-well-being/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local carbon emission zone construction in the highly urbanized regions: Application of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in Shanghai, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bae-local-carbon-emission-zone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S036013232301034X-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The flowchart of the LCEZ construction. Step 1: Luojia1-01 night light image data is the proxy variable of the RTCE map. GWR is geographically weighted regression. Step 2: L is low. M is medium. H is high. the solid line is the three key factors. The dotted line means that n key factors can be selected in the future. The point is POI. the column is BF. the line is RD. A&amp;amp;B represents Dense&amp;amp;sparse forests. C&amp;amp;D represents Farmland&amp;amp;grassland&amp;amp;wetland. G represents the water body.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing spatiotemporal bikeability using multi-source geospatial big data: A case study of Xiamen, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jag-bikeability-multisource/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jag-bikeability-multisource/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposed-bikeability-framework&#34;&gt;Proposed bikeability framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We construct the bikeability evaluation framework by combining the collected multi-source spatio-temporal big data (Figure 1 and Figure 2). The proposed bikeability evaluation framework contains four subindexes, i.e., safety, comfort, accessibility, and vitality, and thirteen influencing indicators, i.e., wind speed, road slope, precipitation, temperature, sky view index, green view index, trajectory sinuosity, air pollution, average speed of trajectory, public transportation accessibility, commercial accessibility, number of trajectory and crowdedness. All indicators used in our framework belong to objective and quantitative measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The proposed bikeability framework.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Street view imagery semantic segmentation process, revised from Chen et al. (2018).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spatiotemporal-analysis-of-bikeability&#34;&gt;Spatiotemporal analysis of bikeability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first present and discuss the results of four subindexes across Xiamen Island on a daily basis from December 21 to 25th, 2020 (Figure 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3. The figures show the daily safety, comfort, accessibility, and vitality of Xiamen Island from top row to bottom row, where from left column to right column respectively represent the dates from 21 to 25th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calculation of the bikeability index requires assigning appropriate weights to each indicators. To determine these weights, we performed a principal component analysis (PCA) on the 13 indicators. The PCA resulted in 6 components, providing a balance between a minimal number of components and reliable explained variance. The relationships between components and indicators are displayed in Figure 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4. The PCA result for 13 indicators indicates correspondence between principal components and original indicators.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temporal distribution of the bikeability index shows a fluctuation throughout the study period, as seen in Figure 5.The temporal distribution of the bikeability index shows a fluctuation throughout the study period, as seen in Fig. 8. On the 21st and 22nd, the average values were recorded as 0.236 and 0.233, respectively. On the 23rd, however, there was a noticeable drop in the bikeability index value, reaching a low of 0.098. Despite this decrease, the values rebounded to 0.188 and 0.185 on the 24th and 25th, respectively. This fluctuation in the bikeability index is mainly due to a rainfall event that occurred in Xiamen on the 23rd. The rainy conditions led to a significant decrease in the safety subindex, which in turn decreased the overall value of the bikeability index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island on December 21st, 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 2020, the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hourly pattern of the bikeability index reveals a different trend compared to the daily change (Fig. 8). As seen in Fig. 8, the hourly bikeability index values exhibit much less fluctuation. The value was recorded as 0.184 at 6:00 a.m. and then gradually increased, reaching its peak at 7:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m. with values of 0.198 and 0.195, respectively. This increase was mainly due to an increase in the vitality subindex, as more people were using shared bicycles between 7:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m. on working days. However, at 9:00 a.m., the value dropped to its lowest point at 0.17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6. Average bikeability of Xiamen Island at 6:00, 7:00, 8:00, and 9:00 a.m., the roads highlighted in red indicate lower levels of bikeability, whereas those in green indicate higher levels of bikeability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further validate our proposed index, we conducted a case study analysis in the central area of Xiamen CR, which is the middle continuous hotspot area. The location of this case study is the shared bicycle cycling hotspot at the intersection of Hubin Nanlu and Hubin Donglu, near the commercial center of Xiamen Wanxiangcheng, between 8:00–9:00 a.m. on December 21, 2020, as shown in Figure 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S1569843223003631-gr10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 7. Case study field validation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study area is centered around the Huarun commercial center, surrounded by a large residential area. During the morning hours, a substantial amount of shared bicycles are used in this region, contributing to a relatively high bikeability index. This highlights the significance of cycling routes in determining the level of bikeability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current cycling infrastructure falls short of supporting high-friendly cycling routes. For example, the road section near Hubin Middle School, which is located in a residential area and has a high demand for commuting, features a high density of shared bicycle stops, catering, shopping, and life services. The natural environment also favors cycling with low slopes, moderate wind speed, low precipitation, suitable temperature, overcast weather, and good air quality. Despite these favorable conditions, this section is congested during the morning rush hour due to a narrow non-motorized lane, slow average speed, and high volume of people commuting and going to school, resulting in low bikeability in this section despite high cycling activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the demand for shared bicycles in hot spot regions is much higher, underscoring the importance of ensuring the availability of bicycles and easy accessibility. As shown in the figure, most road sections in the hot spot area have high densities of parking spots. However, there is a shortage of parking spots on the east side of Huarun Center, leading to a concentration of cyclists in other areas, causing congestion and potentially affecting commuting efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case study showcases how our bikeability index takes into account the purpose of cycling and reflects cyclists’ preferred routes. Nonetheless, there remain disparities between the actual infrastructure, preferred routes, and regional conditions. By integrating the index system with real-time data, it is possible to provide suggestions for enhancing regional cycling conditions. The findings of this research can guide management departments and shared bicycle providers to improve facilities and offer optimal route planning for cyclists to avoid congestion and overcome difficulties in finding available bicycles. In conclusion, the bikeability index can provide comprehensive decision-making recommendations and advance the development of cycling-friendly cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;implications-for-policy-and-practice&#34;&gt;Implications for policy and practice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The variability in the bikeability index across different segments presents an opportunity for transportation planners to enhance cycling infrastructure. Monitoring the spatiotemporal dynamics of bikeability can help identify potential environmental or infrastructure changes and their impact on the community’s level of bikeability. To ensure the relevance of the cycling friendliness index, case studies that incorporate additional infrastructure data are necessary for local comparison of bikeability results, enabling the proposal of landable solutions for varying infrastructure. For instance, the fusion analysis of parking spot electronic fence data and bikeability could expose discrepancies between regional cycling infrastructure and cyclists’ preferences, providing actionable recommendations to government departments and guiding users to cycle in a more bike-friendly manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development and validation of an age-sex-ethnicity-specific metabolic syndrome score in the Chinese adults</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/nc-mets-score-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/nc-mets-score-calculator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We develop a continuous, age-sex-ethnicity-specific Metabolic syndrome (MetS) score based on continuous measures of the five metabolic dysfunctions (waist circumference [WC], triglycerides [TG], high-density lipoprotein cholesterol [HDL-C], mean arterial pressure [MAP], and fasting blood glucose [FBG]).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41467-023-42423-y/MediaObjects/41467_2023_42423_Fig1_HTML.png?as=webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. An overview of the study design.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Shiny app of age-sex-ethnicity-specific MetS score.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A predition method of subtropical forest biomass</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the accuracy of forest biomass estimate using source analysis and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental determinants of childhood obesity: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lancetgh-obesityenvironment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lancetgh-obesityenvironment/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A biomass estimation method by fusing plot data and forest inventory data</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/patent-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of the functional mixed entropy for the explanation of residential and transport CO$_2$ emissions in the urban center of China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-importance-mixed-urban-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.iue.cas.cn/xwzx/kydt/202211/W020221125307842798054.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 The relation between the functional mixed entropy and the GWR mean regression coefficients in 31 cities. The red, yellow, light blue and blue dot represents the Type Ⅰ, Ⅱ, Ⅲ and Ⅳ city, respectively. The numbers follow the city names represent the size order of the urban area. Point A, B and C are hypothetical.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global spreading of Omicron variant of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/gh-covid-19-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/gh-covid-19-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing bicycle-sharing riding friendliness by fusing multi-source heterogeneous spatio-temporal big data</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bikeability-book-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bikeability-book-section/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying urban mass gain and loss by a GIS-based material stocks and flows analysis</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jie-gisbased-material-stocks-and-flows-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jie-gisbased-material-stocks-and-flows-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/6e2b657e-8240-4c6e-a994-ad0948824e47/jiec13252-fig-0001-m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 A framework combining stock-driven material flow analysis (MFA) and geographical information system (GIS) to simulate material metabolism. This improved framework highlights four typical activities that generate material flows, namely, construction, demolition, replacement, and maintenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of two-dimensional copper signatures in human blood for bladder cancer with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cs-corrplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/cs-corrplot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pubs.rsc.org/image/article/2022/SC/d1sc06156a/d1sc06156a-f2_hi-res.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1.  Cu concentration and the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients grouped by cancer grade, cancer stage, age, and gender. Each symbol presents an individual subject. (A and B) Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different grades. “Low” refers to low-grade BCa (n = 16) and “high” refers to high-grade BCa (n = 21). PA = 0.7910 and PB = 0.8324, Mann Whitney test. (C and D) δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different grades. PC = 0.0227 and PD = 0.1854, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (E and F) Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different cancer stages (n = 31 for Ta/T1 and n = 4 for T2/T3). PE = 0.9692 and PF = 0.7699, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (G and H) δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients for different cancer stages. PG = 0.2094 and PH = 0.5604, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test. (I and J) Variation of the Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of all subjects with age. (K and L) Variation of the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with age. (M and N) Variation of the Cu concentration in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with gender (n = 28 for male and n = 13 for female). PM = 0.1083, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test; PN = 0.2924, Mann Whitney test. (O and P) Variation of the δ65Cu value in plasma and RBC of BCa patients with gender. PO = 0.8701 and PP = 0.7349, unpaired Student&amp;rsquo;s two-tailed t-test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing riding friendliness by fusing multi-source heterogeneous spatio-temporal big data</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bikeability-chinses-urban-planning-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/bikeability-chinses-urban-planning-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Plot-Level Model of Forest Biomass: A Combined Approach Using Machine Learning with Spatial Statistics</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g002-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Framework for estimating (a–c) the machine learning models, (d) the P-BSHADE model, and the three models that combine machine learning with the P-BSHADE model ((a,d), (b,d) and (c,d)).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g004-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Prediction performance of the seven different models. (a) MAE and (b) MRE are presented as boxplots for each prediction method, with the median (black horizontal line in the box), interquartile range (25–75% in the box), range 5–95% (whiskers), and outliers (asterisks) labeled (S1 = SVM, S2 = RBF-ANN, S3 = RF, S4 = P-BSHADE, S5 = SVM &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S6 = RBF-ANN &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S7 = RF &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S8 = allometric model, Allome = allometric model, ML = machine learning, and Sp Stats = spatial statistics). Histogram distributions of RMSE and nRMSE for each prediction method are presented in panels &amp;copy; and (d), respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/forests/forests-12-01663/article_deploy/html/images/forests-12-01663-g005-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 Improved accuracy assessment indexes of three combined machine learning and spatial statistical methods are revealed by comparison with three corresponding machine learning methods. Panels (a–d) show the MAE, MRE, RMSE, and nRMSE, respectively; S1 vs. S5 compares S5 with S1, S2 vs. S6 compares S6 with S2, and S3 vs. S7 compares S7 with S3 (S1 = SVM, S2 = RBF-ANN, S3 = RF, S5 = SVM &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S6 = RBF-ANN &amp;amp; P-BSHADE, S7 = RF &amp;amp; P-BSHADE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forest AGB estimates at the plot level play a major role in connecting accurate single-tree AGB measurements to relatively difficult regional AGB estimates. However, AGB estimates at the plot level are plagued by numerous uncertainties. Improving the plot-level model of forest AGB is a key issue in producing accurate AGB maps. A variety of prediction models have been applied to make accurate AGB estimates, all of which have their own advantages and disadvantages. Different approaches complement the advantages of different models and may yield more accurate AGB estimates than would otherwise be produced by using a single method. The main goal of the current study was to determine whether combining machine learning with spatial statistics can improve plot-level AGB estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study explores the prediction performance of different AGB models, and the results show that the model combining the random forest and P-BSHADE models substantially improves the accuracy of the estimates of forest AGB. The results of this study suggest that combining machine learning with spatial statistics improves plot-level AGB estimates. The understanding gained here should help to improve AGB mapping in other regions and in different types of forests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Approaches to Anticipate the Risk of Reverse Zoonosis</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/tree-covid-19-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/tree-covid-19-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;human-activities-exacerbate-the-risks-from-zoonotic-diseases&#34;&gt;Human Activities Exacerbate the Risks from Zoonotic Diseases&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 has been the most widespread zoonotic pandemic to affect humanity in over a century, reflecting the problem of human activities exacerbating the risks of pathogen spillover, such as hunting, butchering, farming, deforestation, reforestation, irrigation, and traveling. Moreover, it has caused ecological feedbacks at local scales (e.g., bi-directional transmission of COVID-19 between animals and humans, which could augment the COVID-19 risk in both animals and humans).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;reverse-zoonosis-of-covid-19&#34;&gt;Reverse Zoonosis of COVID-19&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infection of animals with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) from humans has highlighted the importance of understanding ‘reverse zoonosis’ (zooanthroponosis). Compared with three of the four possible routes of transmission for zoonotic diseases (i.e., animal–human, animal–animal, human–human), which have been well studied and confirmed, human–animal transmission lacks sufficient research due to the rare occurrence prior to COVID-19. Once such reverse zoonosis occurs it may cause the further evolution of viruses and affect the effectiveness of potential COVID-19 vaccines. Given the growing populations of livestock and other domesticated animals, increasing proximity between animals and humans in multiple settings (e.g., wet markets, home, and animal production facilities), and the relatively fewer resources assigned for animal testing during human outbreaks with zoonotic potential (particularly asymptomatic infections), new animals diseases may spread undetected. Proactive consideration of such reverse zoonosis enables the creation of management strategies. Therefore, reverse zoonoses require more rigorous and widespread macroecological and microbial studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Natural Infections of Pet, Zoo, and Livestock Animals as of 11 March 2021 Mapped onto Number of Confirmed Cases in the Human Population.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;building-resilience-against-future-reverse-zoonoses&#34;&gt;Building Resilience against Future Reverse Zoonoses&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reverse zoonoses may cause reduction and even extinction of the wild animal populations susceptible to viruses, which could destroy local biodiversity and ecological balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preventing reverse zoonoses also requires understanding pathogen feedback loops at the wildlife–livestock/pet–human interface. This will require greater capacities and commitments for pathogen discovery, mutation rate detection, and surveillance, in order to improve the prediction of pandemic potential, leading to management actions that interrupt possible pathways of spillover and transmission. Understanding these key evolutionary processes and ecological interactions calls for integrated virus–animal–human–environment surveillance systems. Spatial lifecourse epidemiology also provides a uniform analytical framework to link ecological surveillance to the national disease reporting system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refined water security assessment for sustainable water management: A case study of 15 key cities in the Yangtze River Delta, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jem-water-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jem-water-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars-els-cdn-com.ezproxy2.utwente.nl/content/image/1-s2.0-S0301479721006502-ga1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls in Modeling Asymptomatic COVID-19 Infection</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/frph-covid-19-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/frph-covid-19-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High spatial resolution mapping of steel resources accumulated above ground in mainland China: Past trends and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-high-resolution-steels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-high-resolution-steels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652621007022-gr4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Comparisons between predicted and statistics-based steel stocks in 2015 (a), 2016 (b), 2017 (c), and 2018 (d). The gray shading represents 99% confidence intervals of the log-log regression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652621007022-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 National coverage of in-use steel stocks in 2015 at 1 × 1 km grid level and an example (in a partial view) of modelling area (a), and stocks changes during 1995–2015 (b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The direct and interactive impacts of hydrological factors on bacillary dysentery across different geographical regions in central China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ste-impact-hydrological-factors-bacillary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/ste-impact-hydrological-factors-bacillary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0048969720381407-ga1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0048969720381407-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. The conceptual diagram illustrating the relationship between bacillary dysentery and hydrological factors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Uncertainties Propagation Analysis of CO$_2$ Emissions Gridded Maps at the Urban Scale: A Case Study of Jinjiang City, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/uncertainty-propogation-co2-map-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/uncertainty-propogation-co2-map-rs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphical-abstract&#34;&gt;Graphical abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-ag-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A proposed workflow to analyze the uncertainties caused by gridded model and model input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine-resolution (30 m) maps have a larger spatial variation in CO$_2$ emissions, which gives the fine-resolution maps a higher degree of uncertainty propagation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This indicates a nonlinear change between the sum of the uncertainties for different sectors and the actual uncertainties in the gridded maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nonlinear change can be explained by the “compensation of error” phenomenon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estimating $CO_2$ emissions at the urban scale, including both un-gridded (i.e., administrative unit maps) and gridded maps, cannot avoid the propagation of uncertainties from input to result, which highlights the importance of being aware of uncertainty estimation, especially in gridded maps due to its implications for the precision mitigation of $CO_2$ emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the above mentioned issue, an analytic workflow was proposed to analyze the propagated uncertainties caused by the gridded model and the input for gridded $CO_2$ emission maps. The present workflow used four sub-modules based on Monte Carlo simulations and a bootstrap sampling method to analyze uncertainties, without other detailed open emission inventories. Two of the submodules obtained the corresponding uncertainty of each grid value, generated the uncertainty map caused by the gridded model, and the uncertainties for the sum of each cell (also referred to as propagated uncertainties caused by the model); the other submodules generated the uncertainty distribution maps based on the total emission estimations and spatial proxies (also referred to as propagated uncertainties caused by input).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g001-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytic workflow of the uncertainty propagation in gridded $CO_2$ emission maps. ALs, activity levels; CI, confidence interval; EFs, emission factors; GDP, gross domestic product; KS, Kolmogorov–Smirnov; LUT, look up table; MLE, maximum likelihood estimation; NTL, night time light; PDFs, probability distribution functions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We regarded the gridded maps of $CO_2$ emissions constructed in previous studies as a case study, and applied the workflow to estimate the uncertainties. The estimation of different uncertainties helps decision makers in formulating relevant policies. Uncertainties in total emission estimations aid the determination of emission reduction targets, the corresponding risks for cities and enterprises, and significant emission sources. Uncertainty maps could help to identify locations suitable for developing low-carbon communities. Fine-resolution (30 m) maps have a larger spatial variation in $CO_2$ emissions, which gives the fine-resolution maps a higher degree of uncertainty propagation. Furthermore, the uncertainties of gridded $CO_2$ emission maps, caused by inserting a random error into spatial proxies, were found to decrease after the gridding process. This can be explained by the “compensation of error” phenomenon, which may be attributed to the cancellation of the overestimated and underestimated values among the different sectors at the same grid. This indicates a nonlinear change between the sum of the uncertainties for different sectors and the actual uncertainties in the gridded maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u1&#34;&gt;U1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g004-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2  CDF curve of different $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolution. The upper figures are at 30 m resolution, while the lower figures are at 500 m resolution. The red line is the distribution of the real values, while the blue line is the distribution of the simulated values. (a,e) are the total $CO_2$ emissions, (b,f) are the residential $CO_2$ emissions, (c,g) are the industrial $CO_2$ emissions, and (d,h) are the transport $CO_2$ emissions. KS., Kolmogorov–Smirnov; Sd, Standard deviation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g005-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3  Uncertainty maps made by the gridded model of $CO_2$ emissions in Jinjiang city, at resolutions of 30 m (a–d) and 500 m (e–h). (a,e) show uncertainty maps of total $CO_2$ emissions. (b,f) show uncertainty maps of residential $CO_2$ emissions. (c,g) show uncertainty maps of industrial $CO_2$ emissions. (d,h) show uncertainty maps of transport $CO_2$ emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u2&#34;&gt;U2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g006-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 $CO_2$ emission population (statistic term) distributions of different sectors. The left figures are at 30 m resolution, while the right figures are at 500 m resolution. The red line is the distribution of the real values, and the blue line is the distribution of the simulated values. (a,e) are the total $CO_2$ emissions, (b,f) are the residential $CO_2$ emissions, (c,g) are the industrial $CO_2$ emissions, and (d,h) are the transport $CO_2$ emission.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u3&#34;&gt;U3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g007-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5 Map showing the uncertainty caused by activity levels. (a,b) represent the uncertainty maps of total $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolution, respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;u4&#34;&gt;U4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/remotesensing/remotesensing-12-03932/article_deploy/html/images/remotesensing-12-03932-g008-550.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6 Maps of uncertainty caused by the spatial proxies. (a,b) represent the maps of uncertainty of total $CO_2$ emissions at 30 m and 500 m resolutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation of Health Effect of Short-term Exposure to PM2.5 during Spring Festival: A Case Study of 25 Cities in the Yangtze River Delta(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-health-exposure-shup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-health-exposure-shup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;research-goal&#34;&gt;Research goal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatiotemporal change of health risk of short-term exposure to PM2.5 affected by human mobility during Spring Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Comparison between different machine learning models via spatial cross validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Daily level PM2.5 mapping at 1-km resolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1 The average value and 95% confidence intervals of AF causing by PM2.5 exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;死亡原因&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;$\bar{AF}(+)$(n = 2 858)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;$\bar{AF}(-)$(n = 2 914)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;总死亡&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.28(0.21, 0.33)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.28(0.21, 0.33)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;心血管疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.32(0.24, 0.38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.33(0.25, 0.39)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;高血压疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.19, 0.53)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.41(0.19, 0.54)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;冠心病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.24, 0.41)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.35(0.26, 0.42)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;中风&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.29(0.19, 0.37)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.29(0.19, 0.38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;呼吸道疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.23, 0.42)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.34(0.24, 0.43)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;慢性阻塞性肺疾病&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.29, 0.48)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.40(0.29, 0.49)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 The changing mode of human mobility-health risk in 25 cities of the Yangtze River Delta during the Spring Festival&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://gisersqdai.top/mycv/img/202010fig4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The time variation and OD matrices of AF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should not ignore the health risks of short-term exposure to PM 2.5 caused by human mobility behavior during the Spring Festival, because the estimated average increased risks are from 0.25 to 0.39. The highest risk is more than 0.9. This reveals strong spatiotemporal heterogeneity in the health effect of short-term exposure to PM 2.5. Even the value of risks could change from 0.84 to-0.75 in two days. Most of the travel populations in the Yangtze River Delta have increased the health risk of short-term exposure to PM 2.5 caused by human mobility during the Spring Festival, such as Shanghai and Suzhou, with the exposed populations reaching to nearly 13.2 million and 6 million.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural environment and childhood obesity: A systematic review</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-naturalenvironment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-naturalenvironment/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response of syntrophic bacterial and methanogenic archaeal communities in paddy soil to soil type and phenological period of rice growth</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-responserice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jclp-responserice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652620334636-gr3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Distributions of syntrophs (SPOB and SBOB) and methanogens in the 10 paddy soils (a) at different rice growth stages (b).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0959652620334636-gr5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2. Environmental drivers of syntrophic bacteria composition in the 10 paddy soils (a) at different rice growth stages (b). Pairwise comparisons of environmental parameters and bacterial communities are demonstrated, and the color gradient indicates Spearman’s correlation coefficients. Total syntrophs and SFAS were correlated to each environmental factor, as revealed by the partial Mantel tests. The edge color and width represent the statistical significance and Mantel’s R statistic, respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green space access in the neighbourhood and childhood obesity</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-greenspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-greenspace/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood speed limit and childhood obesity</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-speedlimit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-speedlimit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of high-ash industrial sludge for producing improved char with low heavy metal toxicity</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jaap-corrplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/jaap-corrplot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0165237020303223-gr7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1. Pearson correlation between heavy metal speciation and characteristics of industrial sludge and char samples: (a) F1 + F2 fractions; (b) F3 fraction; &amp;copy; F4 fraction. The color (red to blue) indicates the change in correlation from negative to positive and the size of bubble shows the strength of correlation, which can be expressed by skew-symmetric numbers. Cross shows non-significant correlation between heavy metal and char property (P &amp;gt;  0.05). SA presents BET specific surface area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to bike lanes and childhood obesity: A systematic review and meta‐analysis</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-bikelane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/or-bikelane/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A spatial database of CO$_2$ emissions, urban form fragmentation and city-scale effect related impact factors for the low carbon urban system in Jinjiang city, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-dib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-dib/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More fragmentized urban form more CO$_2$ emissions? A comprehensive relationship from the combination analysis across different scales</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/relationship-co2-fragmentation-jclp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/relationship-co2-fragmentation-jclp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of multi-source data and an analytical framework composed of 3 methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration of the impact of 30-m versus 500-m spatial resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low fragmented mixed and industrial lands affect CO$_2$ emissions negatively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low fragmented residential and public lands affect CO$_2$ emissions positively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactions of factors are weaker at a 30-m resolution than at a 500-m resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the industrial production, transportation, local weather, and fossil fuel use, urban form is the factor that affects energy-related CO$_2$ emissions from human activities secondarily. The major forms of human activity affected by urban form are traffic and residential energy consumption/use emissions. After a wide examination of the relationship between urban higher fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions, scholars found fragmentation of land use areas (i.e. areas designated for human activities or purposes) is associated with greater CO$_2$ emissions. However, the evidences might be biased by the uncertainties from the spatial distribution of emissions (also referred to “downscaling”, or “representation” uncertainty), the delineation of urban fragmentation landscape, and the analysis method, which ignores the spatial heterogeneity. Zuo et al. (2019) published the study in the Journal of Cleaner Production, which compared the relationships between urban form fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions in an urban system through the analytic framework composed of the Pearson correlation analysis, geographically weighted regression (GWR), and geographical detector methods with the use of multi-source data to construct the CO$_2$ emissions maps. The analytical framework can be applied to CO$_2$ emissions research in urban agglomerations, megacities, and small towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/JCLP/JCLP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytical Framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the GWR analysis, the coarse resolution resulted in: 1) positive coefficients of fragmentation metric becoming negative, and 2) greater absolute values of negative coefficients. As to the results of Geographical detector, single factor impact powers and interactions among fragmentation factors showed a weakening effect at R$_{30m}$, but a strengthening and weakening effect at R500m. However, there were common results observed in low-fragmented areas across different scales. That is, in low-fragmented mixed-function areas and industrial areas, the more fragmented the area was, the less the CO2 emission there would be. However, in low-fragmented residential, administrative and public service areas, the more fragmented the area was, the higher the CO$_2$ emission there would be. Therefore, the government should disperse the mixed function zones and industrial parcels with diverse types of land, and build the contiguous residential and public service land in the low fragmentation area of urban system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/JCLP/fig6new.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Geographical detector results for fragmentation factors, PUA, and POID for CO$_2$ emissions from 4 sources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Scale effect” has always been the hot topic in landscape ecology research. Although, there are many studies on the driving force of urban environmental problems by using landscape metrics. Most studies are carried out in regional, continental and global scales. However, in this study, we explored the relationship between the urban form fragmentation and CO$_2$ emissions in the city scale from the perspective of dual resolution sizes and summarized the research conclusions that can be used in urban internal management based on the analysis results of small towns. At the same time, the influence of scale effect and how to choose the appropriate scale were discussed in the discussion section. The rigorous discussion was also made on whether the research conclusion is applicable to medium and large cities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impacts of climate and land use/land cover changes on water yield service in Ningbo region(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lucc-invest-water-yield/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lucc-invest-water-yield/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Carbon Source and Sink Map by Coupling an Ecological Process Model with an Emission Inventory to Study a Carbon Balance</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/masterthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/masterthesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GIS-based high spatial resolution assessment of large-scale PV generation potential in China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/gis-pv-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/gis-pv-energy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PM2.5 Spatiotemporal Evolution and Drivers in the Yangtze River Delta between 2005 and 2015</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/yrt-pm25-drive-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/yrt-pm25-drive-factors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining the Mechanisms that Influence the Surface Temperature of Urban Forest Canopies by Combining Remote Sensing Methods, Ground Observations, and Spatial Statistical Models</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lst-geodector-satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/lst-geodector-satellite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Heavy Metal Sources in the Soil of Riverbanks Across an Urbanization Gradient</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/heavy-metal-geodetector/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/heavy-metal-geodetector/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Walking Environment on Robbery, Snatch and Theft Crime in Urban Area, H City, China(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/crime-geography-walkscore/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;scientific-problems&#34;&gt;Scientific problems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) The influence of urban walking environment on the RST, whether it is in consitent with the theory of good urban walking environment and reducing crime rate in western context?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) What are the characteristics and laws of urban walking environment on RST?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/201812052312.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Analytic framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180601.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Walking environment in urban&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180602.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 3 The results of spatial aggregation(a) and spatial autocorrelation(b)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180603.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4 The spatial distribution of residence probability of suspects under the different distances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180604.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 5 The visualization of correlation coefficient matrix and scatter plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/20180605.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 6 Spatial variation of regression coefficient of GWGLM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed that the walking environment probably has a positive effect on the RST crime in H city, the greater walkability, the more RST. The effects of walking environment probably has spatial heterogeneity features both on RST and the residence probability of suspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wechat-articles&#34;&gt;Wechat articles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/4AOmOlRPz--PQpRbgdiXqw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;【犯罪地理专栏】H市城区步行环境对两抢一盗警情的影响&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the prediction accuracy of forest aboveground biomass benchmark map by integrating machine learning and spatial statistics</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/improved-biomass-map-ei-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution mapping of direct CO$_2$ emissions and uncertainties at the urban scale</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-ei-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/high-resolution-co2-map-ei-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual and Interactive Influences of Anthropogenic and Ecological Factors on Forest PM2.5 Concentrations at an Urban Scale</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-geodetector-multi-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/pm25-geodetector-multi-factors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the effects of different policy tools on China’s emissions reduction innovation(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/energy-conservation-and-emissions-reduction-innovation-journal-cn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/energy-conservation-and-emissions-reduction-innovation-journal-cn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on the effects of command-and-control and market-oriented policy tools on China’s energy conservation and emissions reduction innovation</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/energy-conservation-and-emissions-reduction-innovation-journal-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/energy-conservation-and-emissions-reduction-innovation-journal-en/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape-Scale Simulation Analysis of Waterlogging and Sponge City Planning for a Central Urban Area in Fuzhou City, China</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscape-blue-green-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/landscape-blue-green-space/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The urban underlying surface heavily influences waterlogging. During the urbanization process, vegetation, water, and wetlands are replaced by impervious surfaces, including steel, cement, and other building materials. During the late-1990s, governments began to pay closer attention to the influence of urban underlying surfaces on storm water management. They started to develop low-impact development (LID) practices, which seek to use the landscape to control the water source and reduce the shock loads of storm water. Typical LID practices include green roofs, permeable pavements, and other green infrastructures. With the introduction of the Sponge City concept, China has gradually been introducing LID technology to improve the urban underlying surface and the spatial distribution of landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most previous research of LID analyzed simulation experiments and storm water management at the small-scale level, whereas little analysis has been done at the urban level. Moreover, few studies have considered the influence of the natural green infrastructure (NGI), which refers to landscape that is good at receiving water. Here, we analyzed the urban central area of Fuzhou City, China, using remote sensing (RS) and geographic information system (GIS) data to divide the urban underlying surface into NGI and non-NGI landscapes. We extracted the impervious surface from the non-NGI landscape and used the precipitation-volumetric method to simulate waterlogging scenarios. We determined the area of rainwater submersion by simulation experiments, the change in the NGI landscape by overlaying images of the region, and the association between these features by data mining. Using the change in ecology indices, we ascertained the changing spatial patterns of the NGI landscape and used these findings to formulate suggestions for Sponge City planning in Fuzhou. Overall, our work combines three research themes, urban waterlogging, landscape ecology, and data mining, for a deep analysis of the relationship between the NGI landscape and storm runoff in an urban environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig2new.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1 Flow chart of the study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submerged areas were characterized by high population densities and high levels of human activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1 Simulation results of storm water scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Simulated parameter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Storm intensity($L·S^{-1}·ha^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;163.183&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101.847&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runoff($L·S^{-1}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.342×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.668×$10^6$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maximum submerged depth(m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.943&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged area ($km^{2}$)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.345&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.032&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main submerged area in Fuzhou included the central business district. Numbers of people exposed to the submerged areas of scenarios 1 and 2 were 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28h%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://science.gisersqdai.top/fig.3%28i%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 Visual representation of simulation results for scenario 1 and scenario 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatial association rule mining revealed a strong association between areas that were converted from NGI landscape and areas that were submerged in our simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 2  Results of association rule mining&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rules&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Confidence&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lift&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Submerged=&amp;gt;Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.655&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stay=&amp;gt;No Submerged&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.865&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an area was submerged, then the probability that the area was converted landscape was 21.2%. If an area was not subject to landscape conversion, then the probability that it would not be a submerged area was 99.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the results of this study, we derived the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulation analysis for the central urban area of Fuzhou City, assuming a 100-year storm with rainfall durations of 2 and 4 hours, resulted in submerged depths (areas) of 3.943 m (1.345 km2) and 4.055 m (6.032 km2), to which 12,840 and 46,460 people, respectively, were exposed. Submerged areas were found at locations of stronger human activity, which caused a higher risk of waterlogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The area covered by NGI landscape in the central urban area of Fuzhou City decreased considerably and became more fragmented from 2006 to 2014. Urban residential area covers 40% of the converted landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of association rule mining showed that the submerged area has an important relationship with the NGI landscape conversion that, in turn, makes waterlogging frequent in urban areas. We used EIC to measure the change in landscape patterns and spatial distribution of the NGI landscape. Based on the results, we identified some ecological nodes and corridors and made some suggestions related to the Sponge City planning of Fuzhou City.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Effect of Urban Form on PM2.5: A Case Study of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Urban Agglomerations(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25-leworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-form-pm25-leworkshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simulation Analysis of Waterlogging and the Sponge City Planning Control of Central Urabn Area in Fuzhou City</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/sponge-city-blue-green-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/sponge-city-blue-green-space/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Analysis of Urban Spatial Development Pattern in Beijing Based on the Big Data of Government(Chinese)</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-spatial-development-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/urban-spatial-development-beijing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Planning Location and Design of Smart Campus Based on BIM and GIS：A Case Study of Fujian Normal University</title>
      <link>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/undergraduatethesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gisersqdai.top/mycv/publication/undergraduatethesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
